■
字幕来源：CMCT
后期：阿小小海
你好  黎先生
Why, hello there, Mr. Neff.
今晚工作得很晚
Working pretty late, aren't you, Mr. Neff?
的确很晚  上去吧
Late enough. Let's ride.
你看来面色很差  我没事
You look kind of all in, at that. I'm fine.
保险生意如何  很好
How is the insurance business, Mr. Neff? Okay.
他们无法向我推销保险
They wouldn't ever sell me any.
他们说我太过放浪形骇
They said I have something loose in my heart.
我说是风湿病  是吗
I say it's rheumatism. Yeah?
到12楼了
Twelve.
办公室备忘录
Office memorandum.
黎华达致索偿经理祈巴顿
Walter Neff to Barton Keyes, Claims Manager.
洛杉矶  1938年7月16日
Los Angeles, July 16, 1938.
亲爱的巴顿
Dear Keyes...
你听见时  应该知道这是招认
I suppose you'll call this a confession when you hear it.
我不喜欢  "招认"  这字眼
Well, I don't like the word confession.
我只是想你了解未解答的迷团
I just want to set you right about something you couldn't see...
因为他头头碰着钉
because it was smack up against your nose.
你以为自己是一流的索偿经理
You think you're such a hot potato as a Claims Manager...
能一眼看穿虚假索偿
such a wolf on a phony claim.
也许你是...  但是看看狄先生的索偿个案
Maybe you are, but let's take a look at that Dietrichson claim.
意外和双重保险
Accident and double indemnity.
你的确有点眉目
You were pretty good in there for a while, Keyes.
你说不是意外  对
You said it wasn't an accident. Check.
你说不是自杀  对
You said it wasn't suicide. Check.
你说是谋杀  对
You said it was murder. Check.
你以为已掌握案情
You thought you had it cold, didn't you?
用薄纸包裹  再加粉红色蝴蝶结
All wrapped up in tissue paper, with pink ribbons around it.
完美无暇
It was perfect.
但又不然  你犯了错
Except it wasn't, because you made one mistake...
只是一个小错误
just one little mistake.
估计谁是凶手时  你猜错了
When it came to picking the killer, you picked the wrong guy.
你想知道是谁杀了狄先生
You want to know who killed Dietrichson?
拿稳手上的雪茄  巴顿
Hold tight to that cheap cigar of yours, Keyes.
我杀了狄先生
I killed Dietrichson.
是我  黎华达  保险推销员
Me, Walter Neff, insurance salesman.
35岁  未婚  没有前科
35 years old, unmarried, no visible scars...
直至不久之前
until a while ago, that is.
对  我杀了他
Yes, I killed him.
我杀了他  为了钱...
I killed him for money...
和女人
and for a woman.
我得不到钱  亦得不到女人
And I didn't get the money and I didn't get the woman.
很有趣  是吧
Pretty, isn't it?
一切从去年五月底开始
It all began last May.
那一次
Around the end of May, it was.
我驾驶汽车
I'd been out to Glendale
去格兰代送保单
to deliver a policy on some dairy trucks.
回来途中
On the way back
我记得在洛菲利兹有汽车续保
I remembered this auto renewal near Los Feliz Boulevard.
于是驱车前往
So I drove over there.
有很多十多年前...
It was one of those California Spanish houses...
大家争相兴建的西班牙式房子
everyone was nuts about 10 or 15 years ago.
这一间大约要三万元
This one must've cost somebody about $30,000.
若他已经支付所有的款项
That is, if he ever finished paying for it.
狄先生在吗
Is Mr. Dietrichson in?
谁找他  我姓黎  黎华达
Who wants to see him? My name is Neff. Walter Neff.
若你想推销...
If you're selling something...
我想跟黎先生谈...
Look, it's Mr. Dietrichson I want to talk to...
但我不是推销杂志
and it's not magazine subscriptions.
黎先生不在家  他大约几时回来
Listen, Mr. Dietrichson is not in. How soon do you expect him?
他要回来时就会回来
He'll be home when he gets here, if that's any help to you.
什么事  妮蒂  是谁
What is it, Nettie? Who is it?
有人来找狄先生
It's for Mr. Dietrichson.
我是狄太太  什么事
I'm Mrs. Dietrichson. What is it?
你好  狄太太
How do you do, Mrs. Dietrichson?
我是黎华达  太平保险
I'm Walter Neff, Pacific All Risk.
太平什么  太平保险公司
Pacific all what? The Pacific All Risk Insurance Company.
是关于汽车保险续保
It's about some renewals on the automobiles.
过去两星期
I've been trying to contact your husband
一直想联络你先生
for the past two weeks...
但他不在公司  有何贵干
but he's never in his office. Is there anything I can do?
保险将会在15日到期
The insurance ran out on the 15th.
我不希望汽车
I'd hate to think of your having a smashed fender...
在未获保险覆盖时
or something while you're not...
遇到任何意外
fully covered.
我明白你的意思
Perhaps I know what you mean, Mr. Neff.
我只是在晒日光浴  希望附近没有白鸽
I've just been taking a sunbath. No pigeons around, I hope.
关于保单
About those policies,
抱歉打扰你...
Mrs. Dietrichson, I hate to take up your time, but...
没关系
Oh, that's all right.
请你稍等  我更衣后下来
If you'll wait till I put something on, I'll be right down.
妮蒂  带黎先生到客厅
Nettie, show Mr. Neff into the living room.
客厅会在哪里
Where would the living room be?
请进  但他们锁上酒柜
In there, but they keep the liquor locked up.
没关系  我一向自备钥匙
It's all right. I always carry my own keys.
客厅依然充斥着
The living room was still stuffy...
昨晚的雪茄气味
from last night's cigars.
窗户紧闭
The windows were closed...
阳光从百叶窗帘透射
and the sunshine coming in through the venetian blinds...
尘埃在空气中飞扬
showed up the dust in the air.
钢琴上放了精致相架
On the piano, in a couple of fancy frames,
有狄先生及他与前妻...
were Mr. Dietrichson and Lola...
所生的女儿露娜
his daughter by his first wife.
大沙发后面的桌子上
They had a bowl of those little red goldfish...
放了一盆小金鱼
on the table behind the big davenport.
坦白说
But to tell you the truth, Keyes...
我当时对金鱼
I wasn't a whole lot interested in goldfish right then.
汽车续保或  狄先生女儿露娜毫无兴趣
Or in auto renewals, or in Mr. Dietrichson and his daughter Lola.
我在想楼上的女子
I was thinking about that dame upstairs,
以及她的眼神
and the way she had looked at me...
我想再见到她  近距离
and I wanted to see her again, close...
没有恼人的楼梯分隔我们
without that silly staircase between us.
没让你久等  没有  狄太太
I wasn't long, was I? Not at all, Mrs. Dietrichson.
希望我的脸孔没问题  绝对没有
Hope I've got my face on straight. It's perfect, for my money.
你姓黎  对吧
Neff is the name, isn't it? Yeah.
就像费城姓黎的  你知道那故事吗
With two "F's," like in Philadelphia, if you know the story.
什么  费城故事
What story? The Philadelphia Story.
不如坐下  你谈谈保险的事
Suppose we sit down and you tell me about the insurance.
我丈夫什么也不说
My husband never tells me anything.
是关于你的两部车  喇沙  普利茅斯
Well, it's on your two cars, the LaSalle and the Plymouth.
我们为狄先生处理保单
We've been handling this insurance for Mr. Dietrichson
三年
for three years...
不希望出现断供情况
and we'd hate to see the policies lapse.
你穿了短裤子
That's a honey of an anklet you're wearing, Mrs. Dietrichson.
我刚说过  不希望保单断供
As I was saying, we'd hate to see the policies lapse.
当然
Of course,
我们有三十年宽限期
we give them 30 days. That's all we're allowed to give.
他大概再沙滩油田太忙碌
I guess he's been too busy down at Long Beach in the oil fields.
能否抽个晚上跟我谈一会
Couldn't I catch him at home some evening for a few minutes?
应该可以  但他八时后才回家
I suppose so. But he's never home much before 8:00.
没问题
That's fine with me.
你与汽车会没关系吧
You're not connected with the Automobile Club, are you?
我是太平保险  怎么了
No, the All Risk, Mrs. Dietrichson. Why?
汽车会的人尝试联络他
Somebody from the Automobile Club has been trying to get him.
他们的费用会比较便宜  若你的丈夫是会员
Do they have a better rate? If your husband's a member.
他不是
No, he isn't.
他要先加入
Well, then he'd have to join the club
缴交管理费
and pay the membership fee to start with.
我从不会诋毁别人
I never knock the other fellow's merchandise, Mrs. Dietrichson.
汽车会服务很好
The Automobile Club's fine.
但我的服务也很好
I can do just as well for you, though.
这份保单很具吸引力
I have a very attractive policy here.
只需要两分钟
It wouldn't take me two minutes
就能像你丈夫介绍
to put it in front of your husband.
例如撞车赔偿
For instance, we're writing a new kind of 50% retention feature...
有50％自留额
in the collision coverage.
你是个聪明的保险员
You're a smart insurance man, aren't you, Mr. Neff?
我已经入行11年  做得不错
Well, I've been at it 11 years. Doing pretty well?
只是谋生活
It's a living.
你做汽车保险抑或各类保险
You handle just automobile insurance, or all kinds?
各类  火灾  地震  偷盗
All kinds. Fire, earthquake, theft,
公众责任  集体保险
public liability, group insurance...
工业事故  彻头彻尾
industrial stuff and so on, right down the line.
意外保险
Accident insurance?
当然  狄太太
Accident insurance? Sure, Mrs. Dietrichson.
你的踝环刻了什么
Wish you'd tell me what's engraved on that anklet.
只是我的名字  未请教
Just my name. As, for instance?
菲莉  菲莉
Phyllis. Phyllis, huh?
很好听  但你不肯定
I think I like that. But you're not sure?
我在附近来回了几次
I'd have to drive it around the block a couple of times.
不如你明天晚上八时半过来
Mr. Neff, why don't you drop by tomorrow evening around 8:30?
他会在家  谁
He'll be in then. Who?
我丈夫  你不是想跟他谈吗
My husband. You were anxious to talk to him, weren't you?
是的  但是我已经忘了来意
Yeah, I was, but I'm sort of getting over the idea...
你明白吗
if you know what I mean.
这个州份有时速限制  每小时45里
There's a speed limit in this state, Mr. Neff. 45 miles an hour.
我时速多少  大约90里
How fast was I going, officer? I'd say around 90.
你要从电单车下来给我告票
Suppose you get down off your motorcycle and give me a ticket.
我今次暂且给你警告
Suppose I let you off with a warning this time.
若我不听警告
Suppose it doesn't take.
我会一拳打晕你
Suppose I have to whack you over the knuckles.
我会嚎啕大哭  伏在你的肩膀
Suppose I bust out crying and put my head on your shoulder.
不如伏在我丈夫的肩膀
Suppose you try putting it on my husband's shoulder.
好了
That tears it.
明晚八时半  没问题
8:30 tomorrow evening then. That's what I suggested.
你也会在家  我通常是
Will you be here, too? I guess so, I usually am.
相同椅子子  香水  踝环
Same chair, same perfume, same anklet?
我不肯定是否明白你的意思
I wonder if I know what you mean.
我不肯定你是否不肯定
I wonder if you wonder.
那天下午很炎热
It was a hot afternoon and I can still remember...
我还记得街上的忍冬的气味
the smell of honeysuckle all along that street.
没想到谋杀的气味
How could I have known that murder can sometimes
犹如忍冬
smell like honeysuckle?
也许你会知道  巴顿
Maybe you would have known, Keyes...
当她一提到意外保险的时候  但我没有
the minute she mentioned accident insurance, but I didn't.
我心情愉快
I felt like a million.
我回办公室看是否有邮件
I went back to the office to see if I had any mail.
那天英格活货车司机
It was the day you had that truck driver
来找你
from Inglewood on the carpet.
记得吗  巴顿
Remember, Keyes?
黎先生  祈先生想见你
Mr. Neff, Mr. Keyes wants to see you.
他整个下午嚷着要找你
He's been yelling for you all afternoon.
他是不是只想找人吗
Is he sore, or just frothing at the mouth a little?
帮我放好
Park this for me, will you, sweetheart?
嗨  华达  嗨  佐治
Hello, Walter. Hi, George.
拜托
Come on. Come on, Garlopis.
你休想骗任何人
You're not kidding anybody with that line of bull.
你身陷囹圉  你很清楚  谁说的
You're in a jam and you know it. Says you.
我只要钱  谁说的
All I want is my money. Says you.
你只会见到警察  嗨  华达
All you're gonna get is the cops. Hello, Walter.
这位是英格活的高森姆  我认识高先生
This is Sam Garlopis from Inglewood. Sure, I know Mr. Garlopis.
我帮他草拟货车的保单  你好吗  高先生
Wrote a policy on his truck. How are you, Mr. Garlopis?
我不好  火车被焚毁  对  听着
I ain't so good. My truck burned down. Yeah. Now look, Garlopis.
我每个月都收到上百份的索偿
Every month hundreds of claims come to this desk.
有些是假的  我一看就知
Some of them are phonies, and I know which ones.
我怎知道  有个隐形人告诉我
How do I know? Because my little man tells me.
什么隐形人  在这里的隐形人
What little man? The little man in here.
每次有虚假索偿出现
Every time one of these phonies comes along,
他就会帮我在胃里打结
it ties knots in my stomach.
令我寝食难安
I can't eat.
你就是其一
Yours is one of them, Garlopis.
所以我知道这是虚假索偿
That's how I knew your claim was crooked.
你做了什么
So what did I do?
我今天下午派拖车去你的车房
I sent a tow car over to your garage this afternoon...
他们托起你的货车
and they jacked up that burned-out truck of yours.
知道他们发现什么
And what did they find?
找到一堆整齐的碎纸
They found what was left of a neat pile of shavings.
什么碎纸
What shavings?
你用来浸火水  然后掉下火柴
The ones you soaked with kerosene and dropped a match on.
我只是个可怜人  也许犯了错
Look, Mister, I'm just a poor guy. Maybe I made a mistake.
你可以这样说
That's one way of putting it.
我有点不舒服  祈先生
I ain't feeling so good, Mr. Keyes.
这里  签完就会觉得舒服
Here. Just a minute. Sign this and you'll feel fine.
签什么  说你放弃索偿  这里
Sign what? It's a waiver on your claim. Right here.
这里  这里
Here? Here.
你又做回诚实人  再见
Now you're an honest man again. Goodbye, Garlopis.
但我现在没货车了
But I ain't got no more truck.
我住的地方只值2  000元
$2,600 is lot of dough where I live.
怎么了  你不懂得开门
What's the matter, Garlopis, don't you know how to open the door?
将手放在把手  然后转左
Just put your hand on the knob, turn it to the left.
拉向自己
Now pull it toward you.
对了  谢谢
That's the boy. Thank you, Mr. Keyes.
怎么打扮成这样
What kind of an outfit is this, anyway?
我们是
Are we an insurance company,
保险公司
or just a bunch of dimwitted amateurs...
抑或外行人
to write a policy on a mug like that?
等等  他不是由我评估
Now, wait a minute, Keyes. I don't rate this beef.
我在他的申请表上写着...
I clipped a note to that Garlopis application...
接受风险前要进行详细评估
to have him thoroughly investigated...
我知道  我不是埋怨你
before we accepted the risk. I know you did, Walter.
这是公司的
I'm not beefing at you.
一贯做法
It's the company. It's the way they do things.
这样子他们就什么都不需要做
The way they don't do things!
他们只要
The way they'll write anything
填写销售表格
just to get it down on the sales sheet.
我就负责留意
And I'm the guy
虚假索偿
that has to sit here up to my neck in phony claims...
让他们不会
so they won't
入不敷支
throw more money out the window than they take in at the door.
别转弯抹角  快入正题
Okay, turn the record over, let's hear the other side.
我受够了一群
Well, I get darn sick of trying to
口若悬河的销售员
pick up after a gang of fast-talking salesmen...
他们向危险人士
dumb enough to sell life insurance to a guy...
出售人寿保险
who sleeps in the same bed with four rattlesnakes.
华达  26年了
Walter, I've had 26 years of this and let me tell you,
我觉得...
I'm getting...
你乐在其中
Yeah, and you've loved every minute of it, Keyes.
你敬业乐业
You love it,
只是杞人忧天  你和你的隐形人
only you worry about it too darn much, you and your little man.
你太谨慎行事  将自己逼疯
You're so darn conscientious, you're driving yourself crazy.
你要看日历才敢说
You wouldn't even say today is Tuesday
今天是星期二
unless you looked at the calendar.
再研究这是今年
Then you'd check to see if it was this year's
或是去年的日历
or last year's calendar.
再研究哪间公司印刷日历
Then you'd find out who printed the calendar...
再研究是否
and find out if their calendar
根据世界年历
checked with the World Almanac's calendar.
够了  华达
Now, that's enough from you, Walter.
在我未赶你之前  快滚出去
Now, get out of here before I throw my desk at you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
真的  你这老顽固
I really did, too, you old crab...
总是大叫大嚷  对人呼喝
always yelling your head off, always sore at everybody.
但你骗不了我
But you never fooled me with your song and dance. Not for a second.
我看得出
I kind of always knew that behind the cigar ashes on your vest...
你有广阔胸襟
you had a heart as big as a house.
回到办公司
Back in my office there was a phone message
收到狄太太
from Mrs. Dietrichson...
关于续保的留言
about the renewals.
她不想我明天晚上到府上
She didn't want me to come tomorrow evening.
想改为星期四下午三时半
She wanted me to come Thursday afternoon at 3:30 instead.
我当天的时间排得  密麻麻
I had a lot of stuff lined up for that Thursday afternoon...
包括到圣莫尼卡
including a trip down to Santa Monica...
推销集体人寿保险
to see a couple of live prospects about some group insurance.
但我不断想起狄菲莉
But I kept thinking about Phyllis Dietrichson...
以及她戴踝环的方式
and the way that anklet of hers cut into her leg.
嗨  黎先生  你不进来吗
Hello, Mr. Neff. Aren't you coming in?
我在考虑
I'm considering it.
希望你别介意我更改时间
I hope you didn't mind my changing the appointment.
昨晚不太方便  没关系
Last night wasn't so convenient. That's all right.
反正我只是在看邮票
I was working on my stamp collection anyway.
我在弄冰红茶  你要一杯吗
I was just fixing some iced tea. Would you like a glass?
好  除非你有坏了的啤酒
Yeah, unless you've got a bottle of beer that's not working.
也许有  我不肯定雪柜有什么
There may be some. I never know what's in the icebox.
妮蒂
Nettie.
关于续保  我跟丈夫谈过
About those renewals, Mr. Neff. I talked to my husband about it.
是吗  对  他跟我说会续保
Oh, you did? Yes. He'll renew with you, he told me so.
其实我以为他今天下午在家
As a matter of fact, I thought he'd be here this afternoon.
但他不在  是
But he's not? No.
真可惜
That's terrible.
妮蒂
Nettie!
我忘记了今天女佣放假
Oh, I forgot, today's the maid's day off.
别管啤酒  冰红茶也可以
Never mind the beer. Iced tea will be fine.
柠檬  糖  照你往常做法
Lemon? Sugar? Fix it your way.
既然女佣放假
As long as it's the maid's day off,
我可以帮你
maybe there's something I can do for you.
例如吸尘  有趣
Like running the vacuum cleaner. Fresh.
我以前也推销过吸尘机
I used to peddle vacuum cleaners.
赚得不多  但令我看透人生百态
Not much money, but you learn a lot about life.
读万卷书不如行万里路
I didn't think you'd learned it from a correspondence course.
你何时养成喝茶的习惯
Where'd you pick up this tea drinking?
你不是英国人吧  不  我是加州人
You're not English, are you? No. Californian.
在洛杉矶土生土长
Born right here in Los Angeles.
他们说洛杉矶人来自爱荷华
They say all native Californians come from Iowa.
黎先生  我...  叫我华达
Mr. Neff, I... Make it Walter, huh?
华达  是的
Walter. That's right.
华达
Tell me, Walter,
保险方面你收多少佣金
on this insurance, how much commission do you make?
20％  怎么了
Twenty percent. Why?
我正打算光顾你
I thought perhaps I could throw a little more business your way.
没关系  我想起丈夫
I can always use it. I was thinking about my husband.
担心他在油田工作
I worry a lot about him down in those oil fields.
工作性质很危险  身为管理人员不会吧
It's very dangerous. Not for an executive, is it?
他不只是坐在办公室
He doesn't just sit behind a desk.
他要跟钻油人员到油田
He's right down there with those drilling crews.
令我担心不已
It's got me worried sick.
你是说起重定滑轮可能会掉下
You mean, some dark night a crown block might fall on him?
别这么说  但大致如此
Please don't talk like that. But that's the idea.
有一次一支套管击中工头
The other day a casing line snapped and caught the foreman.
他因背部折断而入院  真糟糕
He's in the hospital with a broken back. That's bad.
这令我紧张不安
It's got me jittery just thinking about it.
假设我丈夫遇上事故
Suppose something like that happened to my husband.
有可能
It could. Well...
你不认为他应该买意外保险
don't you think he ought to have accident insurance? Mmm-hmm.
他可以买那一类保险
What kind of insurance could he have?
用来支付医疗费用
Enough to cover doctors and hospital bills.
例如125星期现金保障
Say $125 a week cash benefit.
最高赔偿达5万元
And he'd rate around $50,000 capital sum.
最高赔偿  那是什么
Capital sum? What's that? In case he gets killed.
假设他死亡  也许我不该这样说
Maybe I shouldn't have said that.
做这一行  每一点都要考虑
I suppose you have to think of everything in your business.
你丈夫会理解
Well, your husband would understand.
我可以向他推销
I'm sure I could sell him on the idea of
意外保险
some accident protection.
不如我跟他谈谈
Why don't I talk to him about it?
你可以尝试  但他很固执
You could try, but he's pretty tough-going.
所有人起初都很固执
They're all tough at first.
他有很多想法
He has a lot on his mind.
不喜欢聆听
He doesn't seem to want to listen to anything...
除了收音机上的棒球赛事
except maybe a baseball game on the radio.
有时候整个晚上
Sometimes we sit here all evening
我们都没交谈
and never say a word to each other.
听起来挺沉闷  我只是坐着编织
Sounds pretty dull. So, I just sit and knit.
你是为了这样而嫁给他
Is that what you married him for?
也许我喜欢他用手指举起羊毛
Maybe I like the way his thumbs hold up the wool.
若他的手指觉得累
Anytime his thumbs get tired...
而我在场时  你就不用编织
Only, with me around, you wouldn't have to knit.
是吗  我敢打赌
Wouldn't I? You bet your life, you wouldn't.
喝少许酒应该无碍
Wonder if a little rum would get this up on its feet.
我想请教你一件事
I want to ask you something, Walter.
我能够不问他
Could I get an accident policy for him
而买意外保险
without bothering him at all?
再说一次
How's that, again?
这对你也方便
It would make it easier for you, too.
你不用跟他谈
You wouldn't even have to talk to him.
我自己有点私己钱
I have a little allowance of my own.
我可以支付  他不用知道
I could pay for it and he needn't know anything about it.
为什么他不用知道
Why shouldn't he know?
因为他不想要意外保险
Because he doesn't want accident insurance.
他很迷信
He's superstitious about it.
很多人都是  真有趣
A lot of people are. That's funny, isn't it?
若有办法
If there was a way to get it like that,
烦恼就一扫而空
all the worry would be over.
你明白吗  华达  当然  我眼睛雪亮
See what I mean, Walter? Sure. I got good eyesight.
你是说在他不知情下购买保险
You mean you want him to have the policy without him knowing it.
保险公司亦不知道
And that means without the insurance company knowing
他不知情
that he doesn't know it.
这是一个设局  有问题吗
That's the setup, isn't it? Is there anything wrong with it?
没有  非常好
No, I think it's lovely.
一个起重定滑轮
Then, if some dark, wet night,
将会击中他...
that crown block did fall on him...
什么定滑轮
What crown block?
但有时定滑轮也身不由己
Only sometimes it can't quite make it on its own,
它需要别人推一把
it has to have a little help.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
当然不一定是定滑轮
Of course, it doesn't have to be a crown block.
可以是汽车撞倒他
It can be a car backing over him,
或者坠楼
or he could fall out of the upstairs window.
诸如此类  余下的是殓房工作
Any little thing like that, just so it's a morgue job.
你疯了  还没那么疯
Are you crazy? Not that crazy.
再见  狄太太  发生什么事
Goodbye, Mrs. Dietrichson. What's the matter?
你无法瞒天过海
Look, baby, you can't get away with it.
你想杀了他  是不是
You want to knock him off, don't you?
你太含血喷人
That's a horrible thing to say.
你以为我是什么人
What'd you think I was, anyway?
来到漂亮妇人
A guy that walks into
的客厅
a good looking dame's front parlor and says:
说  我为你丈夫购买意外保险
"Good afternoon, I sell accident insurance on husbands.
你有一个看不顺眼的丈夫
"You got one that's been around too long?
我可以将他变成现金
"One you'd like to turn into a little hard cash?
笑一个  我就帮你收钱
"Just give me a smile and I'll help you collect. "
你以为我是蠢材  别出言不逊
Boy, what a dope you must think I am. I think you're rotten.
你很不错  只要我不是你丈夫
I think you're swell, so long as I'm not your husband.
给我滚
Get out of here. You bet I'll get out of here, baby.
我一定会走  尽快离开
I'll get out of here, but quick.
我跟她当面对质
So I let her have it straight between the eyes.
她骗不了我  至少今次
She didn't fool me for a minute, not this time.
这是辣手东西
I knew I had hold of a red-hot poker...
要尽快脱手
and the time to drop it was before it burned my hand off.
我停在汽车餐厅
I stopped at a drive-in for a bottle of beer,
喝一杯啤酒
the one I had wanted all along...
想用啤酒
only I wanted it worse now,
抹去冰红茶味道
to get rid of the sour taste of her iced tea...
以及一切感觉...
and everything that went with it.
我不想
I didn't want to go back to the office
回办公室
so I dropped by a bowling alley...
来到第三街与西街的保龄球场
at Third and Western and rolled a few lines...
打了几局  试图挥去那种感觉
to get my mind thinking about something else for a while.
离开时
I didn't feel like eating dinner
我毫无胃口可言
when I left, and I didn't feel like a show.
于是架车回家  泊车后回寓所
So, I drove home, put the car away and went up to my apartment.
外面开始下雨  天色渐黑
It had begun to rain outside and I watched it get dark...
我却没有开灯
and didn't even turn on the light.
但我的心情毫无起色
That didn't help me either.
我心如刀割
I was all twisted up inside...
未能放下心事
and I was still holding on to that red-hot poker.
当时我觉得
And right then it came over me
自己根本从没离开
that I hadn't walked out on anything at all.
我和她之间的关系太强烈
That the hook was too strong...
而且没有结束
that this wasn't the end between her and me.
那只是一个开端
It was only the beginning.
八时正  门铃响起
So at 8:00 the bell would ring
我不假思索就知道那人是谁
and I'd know who it was without even having to think.
好像这是自然不过的事
As if it was the most natural thing in the world.
嗨  你今天下午忘记拿帽子
Hello. You forgot your hat this afternoon.
是吗  你不想我帮你拿来
Did I? Don't you want me to bring it in?
不
Sure.
放在桌上
Put it on the chair.
你怎知道我住在这里  在电话薄
How'd you know where I live? It's in the phone book.
外面在下雨  对
It's raining. Yeah.
脱下外衣坐下吧
Peel off your coat and sit down.
你丈夫出埠
Your husband out?
对  长滩  要建一座新井
Yes. Long Beach. They're spudding in a new well.
他说会迟些回家  大约9  30
He phoned he'd be late. About 9:30.
你还未欢迎我
It's about time you said you were glad to see me.
我知道你不会罢休
I knew you wouldn't leave it like that.
什么  像今天下午
Like what? Like it was this afternoon.
我一定是说了
I must have said something
令你误会的话
that gave you a terribly wrong impression.
你不该这样误会我  华达
You must never think anything like that about me, Walter.
好的  这样不行
Okay. No, it's not okay.
若你不相信我  你想我怎做
Not if you don't believe me. What do you want me to do?
我想你对我好一些
I want you to be nice to me.
好像你第一次来我家
Like the first time you came to the house.
这不可能
It can't be like the first time.
事情发生了  我知道
Something's happened. I know it has.
事情发生了在我们身上
It's happened to us.
我觉得他在看我  但是漠不关心
I feel as if he was watching me. Not that he cares. Not anymore.
他将我紧箍得快要窒息
He keeps me on a leash so tight I can't breathe.
他不是在长滩吗  不用紧张
He's in Long Beach, isn't he? Relax.
也许我不该来
Maybe I oughtn't to have come.
你说得对  你想我走
Maybe you oughtn't. You want me to go?
若你想走  现在
If you want to. Right now?
当然  现在...
Sure, right now.
我为你疯狂  我也一样  华达
I'm crazy about you, baby. I'm crazy about you, Walter.
你头发的香水是什么牌子
That perfume on your hair. What's the name of it?
我不知道  在爱珊达买的
I don't know. I bought it in Ensenada.
我们应该和葡萄酒
You ought to have some of that pink wine to go with it.
起泡的那种  我只有波本酒
The kind that bubbles. All I got is bourbon.
波本酒没问题  华达
Bourbon is fine, Walter.
拿两个杯子
Get a couple of glasses, will you?
要苏打水吗  白开水就可以
Club soda? Plain water, please.
半年前有人
You know, about six months ago
在浴缸被肥皂滑倒
a guy slipped on a cake of soap in his bathtub...
不省人事被淹死
and knocked himself cold and was drowned.
但他买了意外保险
Only he had accident insurance.
他们要求验尸  结果她被拘捕
So they had an autopsy and she didn't get away with it.
谁  他妻子
Who didn't? His wife.
另一宗个案是一个男子中枪
Then there was a case of a guy who was found shot.
妻子说他在清洁枪管
His wife said he was cleaning a gun
不慎走火
and his stomach got in the way.
她结果只得到3尺乘10尺的闹房
All she collected was a three-to-ten stretch in Tehachapi.
也许她觉得值得
Perhaps it was worth it to her.
拿杯子到客厅
See if you can carry that as far as the living room.
这里很雅致  谁替你打扫
It's nice here, Walter. Who takes care of it for you?
一个黑人妇女每周过来打扫两次
A colored woman comes in a couple of times a week.
你自己煮早餐  间中自己榨葡萄汁
Cook your own breakfast? Squeeze a grapefruit once in a while.
其余的在街角的杂货店购买  听起来不错
Get the rest down at the corner drugstore. Sounds wonderful.
只有陌生人
Just strangers beside you.
你不认识他们  也不憎恨他们
You don't know them and you don't hate them.
你不用每天早上坐在桌子对面
You don't have to sit across the table...
向着他和他的女儿
and smile at him and
微笑
that daughter of his every morning of your life.
什么女儿  钢琴上的女孩
What daughter? You mean the little girl on the piano?
露娜  她跟我们同住
Lola. She lives with us.
在他心目中她的地位比我高
He thinks a lot more of her than he does of me.
你想过离婚吗  他不肯离婚
You ever think of a divorce? He wouldn't give me a divorce.
大概因为涉及太多金钱
I suppose because it'd cost him too much money.
他没有钱  自从做油田生意
He hasn't got any money. Not since he went into the oil business.
但你嫁给他时他很富有
But he had when you married him?
是的  而我只想要一个家  有何问题
Yes, he had. And I wanted a home. Why not?
但那不是唯一原因  我是他妻子的看护
But that's not the only reason. I was his wife's nurse.
她长期卧病
She was sick a long time.
她死去时  他很绝望
When she died, he was terribly broken up.
我对他由怜生爱  现在却恨他
I pitied him so. And now you hate him.
是  他对我很刻薄
Yes, Walter. He's so mean to me.
每次我买东西
Every time I buy a dress or a pair of shoes
他就会斥责我
he yells his head off.
他从不让我离家  要我闭嘴
He never lets me go anywhere. He keeps me shut up.
咄咄逼人
He's always been mean to me.
连保单受益人也是他女儿露娜
Even his life insurance all goes to that daughter of his.
完全没有你的份儿
That Lola. Nothing for you at all?
不  我对他来说毫无价值
No. And nothing is just what I'm worth to him.
你在黑暗中
So you lie awake in the dark
听他打鼻鼾时心生一计
and listen to him snore and get ideas.
我不想杀他  我从来不想
Walter, I don't want to kill him. I never did.
就算他喝醉酒掌掴我
Not even when he gets drunk and slaps my face.
但有时你想他死去  或者
Only sometimes you wish he was dead. Perhaps I do.
你希望那是意外
Then you wish it was an accident,
而你手握那份五万元的人寿保险
and you had that policy for $50,000.
那个也是
Is that it? Perhaps that, too.
有一晚从派对架车回家  他又喝醉
The other night we drove home from a party. He was drunk again.
回到车房时他坐着不动
When we drove into the garage,
头部栽栽方向盘
he just sat there with his head on the steering wheel...
引擎仍然在动
and the motor still running.
我当时在想  若我不关掉引擎
And I thought what it would be like if I didn't switch it off...
关掉车房门口  让他留在车上
just closed the garage doors and left him there.
我来告诉你
I'll tell you what it'd be like.
若买下意外保险
If you had that accident policy
而那人死于一氧化碳
and tried to pull a monoxide job...
我们公司有个叫祈巴顿的人
We've got a guy in our office named Keyes.
对他来说
For him a setup like
这类个案只是小儿科
that'd be just like a slice of rare roast beef.
他不消三分钟就知道不是意外
In three minutes he'd know it wasn't an accident.
你不消十分钟就会被强光照射
In 10 minutes you'd be sitting under the hot lights.
不消半小时就会签名自由
In a half-hour you'd be signing your name to a confession.
我没做亦不会做
But, Walter, I didn't do it and I'm not going to do it.
只要牵涉保险公司就没办法
Not if there's an insurance company in the picture, baby.
他们比猴子更懂得把戏
They know more tricks than a carload of monkeys.
若有人死亡  你就死罪难逃
And if there's a death mixed up in it, you haven't got a prayer.
他们一定会要你问吊
They'll hang you just as sure as ten dimes will buy a dollar.
我不想你被问吊  宝贝
And I don't want you to hang, baby.
不要再想了
Stop thinking about it, will you?
我们只是坐着
So we just sat there.
她开始低泣  好像窗外的雨点
She started crying softly, like the rain on the window,
我们一句话也没有说
and we didn't say anything.
也许她已经没再想  但我不是...
Maybe she had stopped thinking about it, but I hadn't.
我无法不想
I couldn't.
这与我
Because it all tied up with something
多年的想法有关
I'd been thinking about for years.
早在我未认识狄菲莉
Since long before I ever ran into Phyllis Dietrichson.
你应该明白  巴顿
Because you know how it is, Keyes.
做这个行业  你总是尝试...
In this business you can't sleep...
识破别人的诡计
for trying to figure out all the tricks they could pull on you.
你就像站在俄罗斯转盘后的人
You're like the guy behind the roulette wheel...
监视客人是否诈骗保险
watching the customers to make sure they don't crook the house.
然后你会想
And then one night, you get to thinking
自己能够诈骗保险
how you could crook the house yourself.
如何做得精明
And do it smart.
因为你已经控制轮盘
Because you've got that wheel right under your hands.
你心里有数
You know every notch in it by heart.
你只需要一个计划
And you figure all you need is a plant out front.
一个诱饵
A shill to put down the bet.
门铃突然想起
And suddenly the doorbell rings...
布局就在眼前
and the whole setup is right there in the room with you.
巴顿  我不是想为自己洗脱罪名
Look, Keyes, I'm not trying to whitewash myself.
我挣扎过  但是屈服了
I fought it, only I guess I didn't fight it hard enough.
这件事涉及五万元  但也涉及一条性命
The stakes were $50,000, but they were the life of a man, too.
一个从没得罪过我的人
A man who'd never done me any dirt, except...
只是她娶了他不在乎
he was married to a woman he didn't care anything about.
而我在乎的女人...
And I did.
你会打给我吗  华达
Will you phone me? Walter?
我恨他  不想回到他身边
I hate him. I loathe going back to him.
你相信我吗  华达  我当然相信
You believe me, don't you, Walter? Sure I believe you.
我受不了  万一他们要吊死我
I can't stand it anymore. What if they did hang me?
他们不会的  宝贝
They're not going to hang you, baby.
但愿如此
It's better than going on this way.
他们不会吊死你
They're not gonna hang you because...
因为你会下手而我会帮你
you're gonna do it and I'm gonna help you.
你知道自己在说什么  我当然知道...
Do you know what you're saying? Sure, I know what I'm saying.
我们会下手  而且要做得正确
We're gonna do it and we're gonna do it right.
我懂得个中道理  华达  你令我心痛
And I'm the guy that knows how. Walter, you're hurting me.
不会又丝毫差错
There's not going to be any slip-up.
没有破绽弱点
Nothing sloppy. Nothing weak.
完美无暇
It's got to be perfect.
明天打给我  但不要在家中  去电话亭
Call me tomorrow. But not from your house. From a booth.
小心自己的举动
And watch your step every single minute.
必须天衣无缝
This has got to be perfect, you understand?
彻头彻尾
Straight down the line.
就是这样  巴顿
That was it, Keyes.
机器开始运作  无人能阻挡它
The machinery had started to move and nothing could stop it.
首先我们要
The first thing we had to do
骗他购意外保险
was fix him up with that accident policy.
我知道他不肯
I knew he wouldn't buy,
但我只需要他在申请表上签名
but all I wanted was his signature on an application.
我要骗他签名
So I had to get him to sign without his knowing
而不自知
what he was signing.
亦要另一个证人在菲莉旁边
And I wanted another witness
让证人听见我向他推销
besides Phyllis to hear me give him a sales talk.
我尝试用你的脑袋思考
I was trying to think with your brains, Keyes...
因为我想在狄先生死去时
because I wanted all the answers ready...
你所提问时的
for all the questions you were gonna spring
所有答案
as soon as Dietrichson was dead.
几晚后  我去了狄宅
A couple of nights later I went to the house.
一切正常
Everything looked fine,
但我不喜欢菲莉带来的证人
except I didn't like the witness Phyllis had brought in.
她是狄先生的女儿露娜
It was Dietrichson's daughter, Lola.
这令我觉得不舒服
And it made me feel a little queer in the belly...
叫她坐在客厅
to have her sitting right there in the room,
玩棋子
playing Chinese checkers...
好像不会发生任何事情
as if nothing were going to happen.
你应该知道
I suppose you realize, Mr. Dietrichson...
由于你不是雇员
that, not being an employee...
你不受到州赔偿保险条例所保障
you are not covered by the State Compensation Insurance Act.
你自保的唯一方
The only way you can protect yourself is
是买个人保险
by having a personal policy of your own.
对  我明白
Yeah, I know all about that.
然后你就会说
The next thing you'll tell me I need...
我需要天灾保险
earthquake insurance and lightning insurance and hail insurance.
若我们买下各类保险
If we bought all the insurance they can think up...
那就会一贫如洗了  对吧
we'd stay broke paying for it, wouldn't we, honey?
令我们一贫如洗的
What keeps us broke is you going out
是你买帽子
and buying five hats at a crack.
在加州谁人会买帽子
Who needs a hat in California?
一分钱一分货
Dollar for dollar, Mr. Dietrichson...
意外保险是价钱最便宜的保险
accident insurance is the cheapest coverage you can buy.
下次谈吧  我今天很累
Well, maybe some other time, Mr. Neff. I had a tough day.
没关系
Just as you say.
今晚搞好汽车保险
Suppose we just settle that automobile insurance tonight.
好
Sure.
只需要在申请表上
All we'll need on that is for you to sign
签名就能续保
the application for renewal.
菲莉  可以不玩吗
Phyllis, do you mind if we don't finish this game?
我觉得很闷  你有别的事做
It bores me stiff. Got something better to do?
是的
Yes, I have.
爸  我可以出去吗
Father, is it all right if I run along now?
去哪里  跟谁  只是安妮  我们去溜冰
Run along where? Who with? Just Anne. We're going roller-skating.
谁  马安妮
Anne who? Anne Matthews.
不又是卓尼诺吧
It's not that Nino Zachetti again, is it?
最好别是那家伙
It better not be that Zachetti guy.
如果让我看见你跟他在一起
If I ever catch you with that...
是马安妮  我说过了
It's Anne Matthews, I told you.
我们只是去溜冰
And I also told you we're going roller-skating.
我约了他在
I'm meeting her
维蒙街法连街交界
at the corner of Vermont and Franklin, the northwest corner...
我已经迟到了
in case you're interested, and I'm late already.
我交代得很清楚  再见  爸
I hope that's all quite clear. Good night, Father.
再见  菲莉再见  狄小姐
Good night, Phyllis. Good night, Miss Dietrichson.
对不起  再见...黎先生
I'm sorry. Good night, Mr... Neff.
再见  黎先生
Good night, Mr. Neff.
身型娇小  说话却厉害
A great little fighter for her weight.
请你在这里签名  狄先生
Now, if you'll just sign these, Mr. Dietrichson.
签什么  汽车续保申请
Sign what? The applications for the auto renewals.
你在新保单发出前会得到保障
So you'll be covered until the new policies are issued.
几时  大约一星期
When will that be? About a week.
我架车往北时会得到保障
Just so I'm covered when I drive up north.
三藩市  帕洛阿尔托
San Francisco? Palo Alto.
他是史丹福人  黎先生
He was a Stanford man, Mr. Neff.
每年都会出席校友宴会
And he still goes to his class reunion every year.
那有什么问题
What's wrong with that?
我不能每年去关心一下
Can't I have a little fun, even once a year?
史丹福的足球很著名
Great football school, Stanford.
你打足球吗  狄先生  左卫
Did you play football, Mr. Dietrichson? Left guard.
几乎入选校队  签哪里
Almost made the varsity, too. Where do I sign?
那条底线
The bottom line.
两份都要  签两次
Both copies, please. Sign twice, huh?
对  一份送给业员
Yes. One is the agent's copy.
我要存档  存档  一式两份  一式三份
I need it for my files. Files. Duplicates. Triplicates.
谢谢
Thank you, Mr. Dietrichson.
关于支票
Don't worry about the check,
我明天到你公司取
I can pick it up at your office some morning.
要多少钱  147  5元
How much you taking me for? $147.50.
今晚到此为止吧  黎先生
I think that's enough insurance for one evening, Mr. Neff.
的确很足够
Plenty.
回来时给我苏打水
Bring me some soda when you come up,
菲莉  晚安  黎先生
Phyllis. Good night, Mr. Neff.
晚安  狄先生
Good night, Mr. Dietrichson.
你的帽子放了在走廊  黎先生
I think you left your hat in the hall, Mr. Neff.
晚安  黎先生
Good night, Mr. Neff.
好了吗  华达  好
All right, Walter? Fine.
他签了  是不是  当然  你亲眼看见
He signed it, didn't he? Sure he signed it. You saw him.
听着  他何时会去帕洛阿尔托
Now, listen. That trip to Palo Alto. When does he leave?
月底
End of the month.
他会驾车吗  他一向驾车
He drives, huh? He always drives.
今次不行  你要叫他坐火车
Not this time. You're gonna make him take the train.
为什么  因为保单适合他坐火车
Why? Because it's all worked out for a train.
每个意外保险
Listen, baby. There's a clause in every accident policy...
都有双重保险条文
a little thing called double indemnity.
保险公司给顾客
The insurance companies put it in
的额外优惠
as a sort of come-on for the customers.
他们在某种情况下会付双倍
That means they pay double on certain accidents.
那些情况几乎没机会发生
The kind that almost never happen.
例如那人在火车上死亡
Like for instance, if a guy is killed on the train...
他们就会付十万而不是五万
they pay $100,000 instead of $50,000.
我明白了
I see. We're hitting it for the limit, baby.
我们要取得最多  所以要坐火车
That's why it's got to be the train.
就听你的话  他会坐火车
It'll be the train, Walter. Just the way you want it.
彻头彻尾
Straight down the line.
嗨  黎先生
Hello, Mr. Neff.
是我
It's me.
有什么事  我在等你
Is anything wrong? I've been waiting for you.
等我  为什么
For me? Why?
我想你载我一程  若你顺路
I thought you could let me ride with you, if you're going my way.
你想去哪里  下山去维蒙
Which way would that be? Down the hill. Down Vermont.
当然  维蒙街与法连街  是吗
Sure. Vermont and Franklin. Northwest corner, wasn't it?
没问题  狄小姐
Be glad to, Miss Dietrichson.
你去溜冰
Going roller-skating, huh?
你喜欢溜冰  我没所谓
You like roller-skating? I can take it or leave it.
但今晚你不会溜冰
Only tonight you're leaving it? Yes, I am.
对  我在家里很不开心
I'm having a very tough time at home.
我爸不明白我  莉菲恨我
My father doesn't understand me and Phyllis hates me.
听起来真糟  所以我间中会说谎
Sounds tough, all right. That's why I have to lie sometimes.
你不是去维蒙街与法连街
You mean it's not Vermont and Franklin?
的确是那里
It's Vermont and Franklin all right.
但不是马尼安  而是卓尼诺
Only it's not Anne Matthews. It's Nino Zachetti.
你不会揭穿我  对吧
You won't tell on me, will you?
我要考虑一下  尼诺不是我爸所说那么差劲
I'd have to think it over. Nino's not what my father says at all.
他只是际遇不好  他在南加州大学读医科
He's just had bad luck. He was doing premed at USC...
晚上在剧院做带位员
and working nights as an usher in a theater downtown.
因为学分不足而被赶出校
Got behind in his credits, flunked out.
然后与上司顶嘴被解雇
Then he lost his job for talking back. He's so hot-headed.
代价真大
Becomes expensive, doesn't it?
我爸大概认为没有配得上他女儿
Guess my father thinks nobody's good enough for his daughter...
除了标准石油的老板
except maybe the guy that owns Standard Oil.
我想他知道  我不能放弃尼诺
I wish he'd see it my way. I can't give Nino up.
船到桥头自然直
It'll all straighten out, Miss Dietrichson.
我想是吧
I suppose it will sometime.
就是这里  黎先生
This is the corner right here, Mr. Neff.
尼诺  过来  尼诺
Nino? Over here, Nino.
黎先生  尼诺...  你好  尼诺
This is Mr. Neff, Nino. Hello, Nino.
我姓卓
The name is Zachetti.
尼诺  不要这样  黎先生送我来
Nino, please. Mr. Neff gave me a ride from the house.
我说起我们的事
I told him all about us.
你为什么跟他说我们的事
Why does he have to get told about us?
不用担心黎先生
We don't have to worry about Mr. Neff, Nino.
我不是担心
I'm not doing any worrying.
只是不想你太高调
Just don't you broadcast so much.
你怎么了
Well, what's the matter with you, Nino?
他是我朋友  我没有朋友
Why, he's a friend. I don't have any friends.
就算有  我也想亲自挑选
If I did, I like to pick them myself. Come on.
她要我载她一程  就此而已
Look, sonny, she needed a ride, so I brought her along.
你有什么不满
Is that anything to get tough about?
露娜  我决定  跟不跟我来
All right, Lola, make up your mind. Are you coming or aren't you?
当然
Of course I'm coming.
别介意他  谢谢载我一程
Don't mind him, Mr. Neff. And thanks a lot for the ride.
你真好人  尼诺
You're awfully sweet. Nino?
她是个好女孩
She was a nice kid.
他就是有点自视过高
Maybe he was a little better than he sounded.
但想起车尾的
But right then
公事包
it gave me a nasty feeling to be thinking about them at all...
放着她父亲
with that briefcase right behind my head
签署的文件
that had her father's signature in it...
就令我浑身不自然
and what that signature meant.
那个签名代表他命不久矣
It meant he was a dead pigeon.
只是时间问题  而且时间无多
It was only a question of time, and not very much time at that.
巴顿  知道洛菲利兹的市集
You know that big market up on Los Feliz, Keyes?
那是菲莉和我挑选的会面点
That's the place Phyllis and I had picked for a meeting place.
我已经几乎有全盘计划
I already had most of the plan in my head...
但还有很多细节需要斟酌
but a lot of details had to be worked out.
她需要载时机到时了解一切
And she had to know them all by heart when the time came.
从今以后  我们必须小心翼翼
We had to be very careful from now on.
不能让人看见我们一起
We couldn't let anybody see us together.
我们甚至不能在电话上交谈
We couldn't even talk to each other on the telephone.
不能从她家中及我的办公室
Not from her house or at my office, anyway.
她每天早上11时
So she was to be in the market every morning about 11:00,
会到市集购物
buying stuff.
我随时都可以碰上她
And I could sort of run into her there any day I wanted to.
装着偶然
Sort of accidentally on purpose.
华达  我想...  别那么大声
Walter, I wanted to... Not so loud.
我从昨天起就想跟你谈
I wanted to talk to you, ever since yesterday.
让我先说  事情已搞定
Let me talk first. It's all set.
保单已经批核  就在我的口袋里
The accident policy came through. I've got it in my pocket.
还有他的支票  我在油田见过他
I got his check, too. I saw him down in the oil fields.
他以为是支付汽车保险
He thought he was paying for the auto insurance.
支票抬头
The check's just made out to the company,
只是保险公司
so it could be for anything.
但你要寄出汽车保险的支票
But you have to send a check for the auto insurance, see?
不会有问题
It'll be all right that way,
其中一部车是你的名下
because one of the cars is in your name.
打开手袋  快点
Open your bag. Quick.
你能打开保险箱吗
Can you get in the safe-deposit box?
对  我俩都有钥匙
Yes. We both have keys. Fine.
好  但暂时不会放保单进去  我会再告诉你
But don't put the policy in there yet. I'll tell you when.
你从没见过或碰过
Remember, you never saw it, you never even touched it,
记得吗
you understand?
我不是傻瓜  好的  他何时会搭火车
I'm not a fool. Okay. When is he leaving on the train?
他不去了  什么
That's just it. He isn't going. What?
我就是想跟你说  行程取消了
That's what I've been trying to tell you. The trip is off.
发生什么事
What happened?
先生  可以帮我拿婴儿食物
Mister, could you reach me that package of baby food?
上面那一包
That one up there?
不明白为何总是放在上面
I don't know why they always put what I want on the top shelf.
继续说  我在听
Go ahead. I'm listening.
他从油井掉下  跌断腿打石膏
He had a fall-down at the well. Broke his leg. It's in a cast.
跌断腿  现在怎办
Broke his leg? What do we do now, Walter?
只有等待  等待什么
Nothing. We just wait. Wait for what?
直至他能再搭火车
Until he can take the train.
我说过一定要搭火车
I told you it's got to be the train.
我们不能等  我再也受不了
But we can't wait. I can't go on like this.
我们不能
Look, we're not gonna grab a hammer
拿起追子杀人
and do it quick, just to get it over with.
还有其他办法  不可以用其他方法
There are other ways. We're not gonna do it other ways.
但不可以就此作罢
But we can't leave it like this.
若他发现
What do you suppose would happen
意外保险怎么办
if he found out about the accident policy?
我明白  但总好过被判死刑
Plenty. But not as bad as sitting in that death house.
别说这种话
Don't ever talk like that.
我们要冷静
Don't let's start losing our heads, that's all.
我快要失去耐性
It's not our heads. It's our nerve we're losing.
借过
Excuse me.
我们一定要做得正确
We're gonna do it right. That's all I said.
最难忍受就是等待
It's the waiting that's getting me.
我很难过
It's getting me just as bad, baby.
但是我们一定要等  你说得对
But we've got to wait. Maybe we have, Walter, only...
没有你日子很难过  好像我们之间有一道墙壁
it's so tough without you. It's like a wall between us.
我要走了  我无时无刻想念你
I better go, baby. I'm thinking of you every minute.
整整一个星期  我都没有找她
After that, a full week went by and I didn't see her once.
我试图忘记她及整项计划
I tried to keep my mind off her and off the whole idea.
可能命运
I kept telling myself
在幕后操纵
that maybe those Fates they say watch over you...
弄断他的腿  让我抽身而退
had gotten together and broken his leg to give me a way out.
那天是6月15日  你或者记得  巴顿
Then it was the 15th of June. You may remember that date, Keyes.
你在下午三时来我的办公室
You came into my office around 3:00 in the afternoon.
嗨  巴顿
Hello, Keyes.
我刚从卢顿的办公室回来
I just came from Norton's office.
半年度营业报告公布了
The semiannual sales records are out.
你是最佳销售员
You're high man, Walter.
连续第二次  恭喜
That's twice in a row. Congratulations.
谢谢  想喝一杯吗
Thanks. How would you like a cheap drink?
你有兴趣减薪五十元吗
How would you like a $50 cut in salary?
我应该现在就笑吗  我说真的
Do I laugh now or wait till it gets funny? No, I'm serious.
我刚跟卢敦谈过
I've just been talking to Norton.
我的文件堆积如山
Too much stuff piling up on my desk.
压力太大
Too much pressure on my nerves.
整晚无法入睡
I spend half the night walking up and down in my bed.
需要一位助手  我即时想到你
I've got to have an assistant and I thought of you.
我  为什么找我
Me? Why pick on me?
因为我觉得你会很称职
Well, because I've got a crazy idea you might be good at the job.
太荒谬了  我是销售员
That's crazy, all right. I'm a salesman.
对  你长袖善舞  能文能武
Yeah. A peddler, a gladhander, a backslapper.
做销售员实在太浪费
You're too good to be a salesman.
人人都配得上做销售员
Nobody's too good to be a salesman. Phooey!
你们只是按门钟
All you guys do is just ring doorbells
说一番无聊话
and dish out a smooth line of monkey talk.
你最不满意是减薪五十元吧
What's troubling you is that $50 cut, isn't it?
人人都会觉得不满意
Well, that'd trouble anybody. Now look, Walter.
听着  这工作需要头脑与正义感
The job I'm talking about takes brains and integrity.
所需得胆量超过五十元得价值
It takes more guts than there is in 50 salesmen.
在保险业中最炙手可热得职位
It's the hottest job in the business.
对  但那是办公室工作
Yeah, but it's still a desk job.
我不想锁在办公室  办公室工作
I don't want to be nailed to a desk. Desk job?
这是你的想法
Is that all you can see in it?
朝九晚五  文风不动
Just a hard chair to park your pants on from 9:00 to 5:00, huh?
大堆文件
Just a pile of papers to shuffle around,
飞来飘去
and five sharp pencils...
五支铅笔和便条纸
and a scratch pad to make figures on,
心不在焉地乱涂
maybe a little doodling on the side.
我可不是这样认为
Well, that's not the way I look at it, Walter.
对我来说  索偿专员是外科医生
To me, a claims man is a surgeon,
办公桌是手术台
that desk is an operating table...
铅笔是手术刀及骨盘
and those pencils are scalpels and bone chisels.
纸张不只是
And those papers are not just
索偿表格及数据
forms and statistics and claims for compensation.
他们是活生生  充满戏剧感
They're alive. They're packed with drama...
包含峰回路转地希望与梦想
with twisted hopes and crooked dreams.
索偿专员是医生  侦探...
A claims man, Walter, is a doctor and a bloodhound and a...
谁  好  等一下
Who? Okay, hold on a minute.
索偿医生是医生
A claims man is a doctor
侦探  警察及法官
and a bloodhound and a cop and a judge and a jury...
陪审团  告解神父  集于一身
and a father confessor, all in one.
你居然说没有兴趣
And you want to tell me you're not interested?
你不想用脑袋工作
You don't want to work with your brains?
你只想用手指按门钟
All you want to work is with your finger on the doorbell...
每星期多赚几块  有女人找你
for a few bucks more a week. There's a dame on your phone.
我是黎华达  我要打给你
Walter Neff speaking. I had to call you, Walter.
事关紧急  有人在旁边吗
It's very urgent. Are you with somebody?
是  我可以再回电  玛琪
Yes, I am. Can't I call you back, Margie?
不可以  很快就说完
No, you can't. I've only got a minute. It can't wait.
他今晚要出发  坐火车  你在听吗
Listen. He's going tonight. On the train. Are you listening?
华达  我在听  玛琪
Walter? Yeah. I'm listening, Margie.
有话快说  他要那拐杖
Only, make it snappy, will you? He's on crutches.
医生说
The doctor says
若他小心就可以出发
he can go if he's careful. The change will do him good.
实在太好了  如你所愿  他会坐火车
It's wonderful, Walter. Just the way you wanted it, on a train.
他拿着拐杖不是更好吗
Only with the crutches it makes it much better, doesn't it?
对  非常好
Yeah. Yeah, that's 100% better.
稍等一下
Hold the line a minute, will you?
巴顿  我去办公室找你
Keyes, suppose I join you in your office?
没关系  我等你
That's all right. I'll wait.
叫她不要说一整天
Only tell her not to take all day.
继续说
Go ahead.
是格兰岱的10时15分火车  我开车送他
It's the 10:15 from Glendale. I'm driving him.
仍然是那条黑暗的街道
It's still the same dark street, isn't it?
讯号是三下响号  好  还有别的
And the signal is three honks on the horn. Okay. Anything else?
没有
No.
哦...
Oh, uh...
你挑选了什么颜色
what color did you pick?
蓝色  海军蓝色  左边打石膏
Blue. Navy blue. And the cast is on his left leg.
恩
Mmm-hmm.
好  没问题
Yeah, that suits me fine.
对了  华达  我在打冷战
This is it, Walter. I'm shaking like a leaf.
但我们会彻头彻尾
But it's straight down the line for both of us.
我爱你  华达  再见
I love you, Walter. Goodbye.
对不起  巴顿
Sorry, Keyes. What's the matter?
又有女孩追求你  可能这与我无关
Dames chasing you again? Or still? Or is it none of my business?
若我说那是客人...
If I told you it was a customer...
玛琪  她大概用酒瓶子喝酒
Margie. I bet she drinks from the bottle.
你为什么还不成家立正室
Why don't you settle down and get married, Walter?
你又为什么呢  我几乎结婚  很多年前的事
Why don't you, for instance? I almost did, once. Long time ago.
巴顿  我要打电话给客人
Now look, Keyes, I've got to call on a prospect.
连教堂也挑选了
Even had the church picked out, the dame and I.
她有一件荷边装饰的缎裙
She had a white satin dress with flounces on it.
我正走去珠宝店买戒指
I was on my way to the jewelry store to buy the ring.
突然有个不祥预兆
And then suddenly that little man in here started working on me.
于是折返找她
So you went back and had her investigated?
对  事情终于水落石出
Yeah. And the stuff that came out...
她自从16岁就开始染发
She'd been dyeing her hair ever since she was 16.
她有家族遗传的兴奋忧郁症  是母系遗传病
There was a manic depressive in her family, on her mother's side.
她已经有丈夫
She already had one husband.
他是巴尔的摩职业桌球手...
He was a professional pool player in Baltimore.
我大致明白
And as for her brother... I get the general idea.
她水性杨花
She was a tramp from a long line of tramps.
对  好的
Yeah. All right, all right.
我该怎样跟尼诺说那份工作
Now what do I say to Norton? What about this job I want you for?
我不会接受
I don't think I want it, Keyes.
谢谢你  好吧
Thanks just the same. Fair enough.
我挑选你
Only get this, I picked you for the job...
不是因为你聪明
not because I think you're so darn smart...
而是因为你
but because I thought you were a shade less dumb
不像打扮般肤浅
than the rest of the outfit.
我大概想错了  你并不高明
Guess I was wrong. You're not smarter, Walter.
只是比较高
You're just a little taller.
是的  巴顿
Yes, Keyes.
我所说的命运只是拖延了我
Those Fates I was talking about had only been stalling me off.
现在万事具备  一触即发
Now they had thrown the switch. The gears had meshed.
给人思考的时间已经溜走
The time for thinking had all run out.
我希望自己
I wanted my movements accounted
能考虑至最后一刻
for up to the last possible moment.
当我离开办公室
So when I left the office
我假意的将运算薄留在桌上
I put my rate book on the desk as if I had forgotten it.
这是我不在场证据之一
That was part of my alibi.
然后就是按照时间表
From here on, it was a question of following the timetable...
按部就班
move by move.
我大约7时回家  将车驶到车房
I got home about 7:00 and drove right into the garage.
这是另一个步在场证据
This was another item to establish my alibi.
嗨  黎先生  你好  查理
Hi, Mr. Neff. Hello, Charlie.
请帮我洗车
How about giving the heap a wash job?
你何时要
How soon you gonna want it?
我还有几部车
I got a couple cars ahead of you.
没所谓
Any time you get to it, Charlie.
我今晚留在家  好
I'm staying in tonight. Okay.
会寓所后我打给舒路尔
Up in my apartment I called Lou Schwartz...
与我同一办公室的保险员
one of the salesmen that shared my office.
他住在西木区
He lived in Westwood,
那是长途电话  会有记录
so it was a toll call and there'd be a record of it.
我跟他说我忘记拿运算薄
I told him I'd forgotten my rate book and needed some dope...
需要公众责任公债的资料...
on the public liability bond I was figuring.
我换上
I changed into
海军蓝色的西装
a navy blue suit like Dietrichson was going to wear.
舒路尔回复我  并给我大量数据
Lou Schwartz called me back and gave me a lot of figures.
我在口袋里放了毛巾及纸
I stuffed a hand towel and a roll of adhesive into my pockets...
让我可以假装
so I could fake something
打石膏的短腿
that looked like a cast on a broken leg.
接着  我在电话里放了一张卡片
Next, I stuck a card inside the telephone box...
若电话铃响过  卡片就会掉下
so that it would fall down if the bell rang.
那么若有人打来  我就会知道
That way I'd know if anybody had called me while I was away.
然后在门铃
Then I did the same thing to the doorbell
亦放了一张卡片
in case anybody came to see me.
我从佣人楼梯离开大厦  没人看见我
I left the apartment by the service stairs. Nobody saw me.
我从寓所前往狄宅
I walked all the way from my apartment to the Dietrichson house.
我不想搭巴士
I didn't want to take the bus...
以免有人
because there was always the chance
看见我
that someone might remember seeing me on it.
我就是如此谨慎
I was being that careful.
我又嗅到忍冬的气味
I could smell that honeysuckle again.
但这次更强烈  现在是晚上
Only it was even stronger, now that it was night.
我悄悄地打开车房门口
I slid the garage door open as quietly as I could.
她就如我所说将车泊好
She'd backed the sedan in, just the way I told her to.
我认为这样会比较安全
I'd figured it was safer that way...
以防他在她开车前上车
in case he got into the car before she drove it out.
我来到车的后座
I got into the back of the car.
躺在地上等待
I lay there on the floor and waited.
我只想到前往
All the time I was thinking about
火车站的黑暗街头
that dark street on the way to the station...
我将会在火车站下手
where I was to do it...
以及那三下作讯号的响号
and the three honks on the horn that were to be the signal.
十分钟后  他们就下来
About 10 minutes later they came down.
你还好吧  我很好
All right, honey? Yeah, I'm all right.
我马上开车出来
I'll have the car out in a second.
慢慢来  还有时间  对
Take it easy, honey. We've got lots of time. Yeah.
记得医生怎说
Remember what the doctor said. If you get careless...
若你不小心也许会变成长短腿
you might end up with a shorter leg.
那又怎样  打断另一条就可以
So what? I could break the other one and match them up again.
离开我你觉得很高兴  是吗
It makes you feel pretty good to get away from me, doesn't it?
只是四天  最迟星期一就回来
It's only for four days. I'll be back Monday at the latest.
不是这条街  为什么在这里转
This is not the right street. Why did you turn here?
你在做什么
What are you doing that for?
按响号做什么
What are you honking the horn for?
你应付搬运工人及列车员
You take care of the redcap and the conductor.
不用担心  尽量不要让他们接近我
Don't worry. Keep away from me as much as you can.
跟他们说我不需要协助
Tell them I don't want to be helped.
我说过不用担心  华达
I said, don't worry, Walter.
火车离开后你就启程
You start as soon as the train leaves.
到达炼厂后
When you get to the refinery,
离开公路驶到泥路
turn off the highway onto the dirt road.
十分之八里的路程
From there it's exactly eight-tenths of a mile...
记得吗
to the dump beside the tracks. Remember.
我全都记得  不要超速
I remember everything. No speeding.
你不会希望被警方截停  而他在后面
You don't want any cops stopping you with him in the back.
我们已经彩排过很多次
Walter, we've been through all that so many times.
离开公路时关掉所有灯光
When you leave the highway, turn off all your lights.
我会到瞭望台
I'll be back on the observation platform.
我会尽快在预定位置跳车
I'll drop off as close to the spot as I can.
火车经过后闪两次灯光
Let the train pass, then dim your lights twice.
三藩市火车  小姐  9号车  11号室
San Francisco train, lady? Car 9, section 11.
只是我丈夫
Just my husband.
9号车  11号室  这边请
Car 9, section 11? This way please.
谢谢  我丈夫不需要别人协助
Thank you. My husband doesn't like to be helped.
8号车在那里
Car number 8. Up there.
9号车  11号室  谢谢
Car 9, section 11. Thank you.
车票在这里  小心保护腿
Here're the tickets. Take good care of yourself with that leg.
对  你架车回家要小心
Yeah. You take it easy driving home.
我想念你  宝贝  11号室
I'll miss you, honey. Section 11, sir.
全部登车  谢谢
All aboard! Thank you.
再见  全部登车
Goodbye, honey. All aboard!
祝你好运
Good luck, honey.
服务员  请帮我弄好座位
Porter, will you make up my berth right away?
是
Yes, sir.
我去瞭望台抽一口烟
I'm going back to the observation car for a smoke.
是  这边
Right this way, sir.
你要坐吗
Like a chair?
不  我想站一下
No, thanks. I'd rather stand.
你去很远吗  帕洛阿尔托
You going far? Palo Alto.
我姓谢
My name's Jackson.
要去美德福  俄勒岗美德福
I'm going all the way to Medford. Medford, Oregon.
我曾试过断腿
I had a broken arm once.
那个石膏令你痕痒难耐  是吗
That darn cast itches something fierce, doesn't it?
我差点疼得发疯
I thought I'd go crazy with mine.
帕尔阿尔托是个不错的小镇  你是史丹福人
Palo Alto's a nice little town. You a Stanford man?
我以前是  你似乎留下了东西
I used to be. I'll bet you left something behind.
我经常如此
I always do.
我的雪茄盒
My cigar case.
应该在我的车厢里的外衣
I guess I left it in my overcoat back in the section.
你想自己卷支烟吗  未请教...
Would you care to roll yourself a cigarette, Mister...
我姓狄
Dietrichson.
不  我想抽雪茄
No thanks, I really prefer a cigar.
也许服务员可以...
Maybe the porter could... Well, I could get your cigars for you.
我帮你去拿  狄先生  希望不会麻烦到你
Be glad to, Mr. Dietrichson. If it's not too much trouble.
9号车  11号室  9号车  11号室
Car 9, section 11. Car 9, section 11.
乐意效劳
With pleasure.
没问题  事不宜迟
Okay. This has gotta be fast.
拿着他的帽子  去路轨拾回拐杖
Here, take his hat. Pick up the crutches back on the tracks.
好了  行了
Okay, baby. That's it.
开车吧
All right. Let's go.
回途中我们再彩排一次...
On the way back, we went over once more...
她在审讯时的做法
what she was to do at the inquest...
假如有审讯  以及保险的问题
if they had one, and about the insurance, when that came up.
我担心她
I was afraid she might go to pieces a little,
会精神崩溃
now that we had done it.
但她表现出色  毫不紧张
But she was perfect. No nerves.
没有半滴眼泪  连眨  眼都没有
Not a tear, not even a blink of the eyes.
她在我寓所之外一条街放下我
She dropped me a block from my apartment house.
华达  怎么了  你不吻我
Walter, what's the matter? Aren't you going to kiss me?
彻头彻尾  不是吗
It's straight down the line, isn't it?
我爱你  华达  我也爱你
I love you, Walter. I love you, baby.
11时2分
It was two minutes past 11:00,
我从雇人楼梯返家
as I went up the service stairs again.
今次亦没人看见我
Nobody saw me this time either.
我回家后检查门铃
In the apartment I checked the bells.
卡片没有动  没人打来  没访客
The cards hadn't moved. No calls. No visitors.
然后我又换衣服
Then I changed my clothes again.
只剩下一件事未完成
That left one last thing to do.
我要去车房  我想查理再看见我
I had to go down to the garage. I wanted Charlie to see me again.
你要用车吗  我还未洗好
You gonna use your car, after all? I'm not quite through.
没关系
Well, that's all right, Charlie.
我只是去杂货店买东西
Just going up to the drugstore to get something to eat.
我一直在工作
Been working upstairs all night.
有点胃痛
My stomach's getting a little sore at me.
是的  先生
Yes, sir, Mr. Neff.
事情终于告一段落
That was all there was to it.
没有犯错  没有忽略细节
Nothing had slipped, nothing had been overlooked.
没有事情能泄漏我们的秘  密
There was nothing to give us away.
但是当我步向
And yet, Keyes,
杂货店时  巴顿
as I was walking down the street to the drugstore...
我突然觉得每个步骤都犯了错误
suddenly it came over me that everything would go wrong.
听来很疯狂  但这是真的
It sounds crazy, Keyes, but it's true, so help me.
我听不见自己的脚步声
I couldn't hear my own footsteps.
那是死人的脚步声
It was the walk of a dead man.
那是我毕生最漫长的一夜
That was the longest night I ever lived through, Keyes...
接下来一天更难熬
and the next day was worse,
报章已经报道事件
when the story had broke in the papers...
公司的人开始讨论事件
and they started talking about it at the office...
后天  你着手研究
and the day after that, when you started digging into it.
我觉得手在抖震
I kept my hands in my pockets
所以伸进口袋
because I thought they were shaking.
并带上太阳眼睛  不让人看见我
I put on dark glasses so people couldn't see my eyes.
然后再脱下
And then I took them off again
让他们不觉得奇怪
so they wouldn't get to wondering why I wore them.
我尝试保持冷静  但是...
I tried to hold myself together, but...
我感到自己紧张得快要撕裂
I could feel my nerves pulling me to pieces.
华达  是  巴顿
Oh, Walter? Hello, Keyes.
过来  大老板想见我们
Come along. The big boss wants to see us.
狄先生的个案  想必也是
The Dietrichson case? Must be.
有问题吗  他死了
Anything wrong? Well, the guy is dead.
而我们受保  这将会令我们  花费一笔
We had him insured and it's gonna cost us dough.
这永远是错事
That's always wrong.
暂时有什么资料  验尸报告
What have they got so far? Autopsy report.
没有心脏病
No heart failure, no apoplexy,
中风或任何疾病
no predisposing medical cause of any kind.
他死于颈骨折断
Died of a broken neck.
何时审讯  今早进行了
When's the inquest? Had it this morning.
妻子及女儿已经认尸
His wife and daughter made the identification.
火车职员
The train people
及乘客说
and some of the passengers told how he went through...
他走到了望台
to the observation car.
事情在45分钟内发生  法庭裁定  意外死亡
It was all over in 45 minutes. Verdict? Accidental death.
警察有何想法
What do the police figure?
他被拐杖绊倒  掉下火车
That he got tangled up in his crutches and fell off the train.
他们很满意
They're satisfied.
不会追查下去  来吧  华达
It's not their dough. Come on, Walter.
好  谢谢
All right. Thank you very much, gentlemen.
现在法律情况已经很清晰
I believe the legal position is now clear.
请留守岗位  我也许需要你
Please stand by. I may need you later.
请进  祁先生  还有你  黎先生
Come in, Mr. Keyes. You, too, Mr. Neff.
你觉得今天很暖吗  祁先生
You find this an uncomfortably warm day, Mr. Keyes?
抱歉  我不知道这是正式会议
I'm sorry, Mr. Norton, but I didn't know this was formal.
两位请坐谢谢
Sit down, gentlemen. Thank you.
有新进展吗
Any new developments?
我刚打长途电话给姓谢的
I just talked to this Jackson long distance,
在俄勒冈美德福
up in Medford, Oregon.
谁
Who's Jackson?
他是最后看见狄先生在生的人
He's the last man who saw Dietrichson alive.
他们在了望台一起谈话
They were out on the observation platform together, talking.
狄先生想抽雪茄
Dietrichson wanted a cigar and so Jackson went back...
谢先生帮他拿雪茄盒
to get Dietrichson's cigar case for him.
回到了望台时狄先生已失踪
When he returned to the observation platform, no Dietrichson.
谢先生当时不以为然
Well, Jackson didn't think anything was wrong until...
直至电报送达在圣巴巴拉的火车
a wire caught up with the train at Santa Barbara.
他们在布班附近  路轨发现狄先生的尸体
They found Dietrichson's body on the tracks near Burbank.
雪茄盒的事很有趣
Very interesting about the cigar case.
还有别的吗  不多
Anything else? No, not much.
狄先生的秘书说
Dietrichson's secretary says
她不知道保险的事
she didn't know anything about the policy.
狄先生的女儿
There's a daughter,
只记得黎华达
but all she remembers is Neff talking to her father...
有一晚他们在家中谈意外保险
about accident insurance at their house one night.
我起初说服不了
I couldn't sell him at first.
狄先生反对  他说他会再考虑
Mr. Dietrichson opposed it. He said he'd think it over.
其后我在油田见他时他答应了
Later I saw him in the oil fields and closed him.
他签了申请表并给我支票
He signed the application and gave me his check.
你的确是一流的营业员
A fine piece of salesmanship that was, Mr. Neff.
不要将责任推给他
Well, there's no sense in pushing Neff around.
他是全公司最优秀的营业员
He's got the best sales record in the office.
他怎知道顾客
Are your salesmen supposed to know a customer
会从火车掉下
is going to fall off the train?
从火车掉下  你肯定吗
Fall off a train? Are we sure Dietrichson fell off the train?
我不明白  你不明白
I don't get it. You don't, Mr. Keyes?
那你有何高见
Then what do you think of this case?
这份保单将会耗费巨资
This policy might cost us a great deal of money.
它有双重保险条文
As you know, it contains a double indemnity clause.
你有何意见
Just what is your opinion?
没有  没有预感
No opinion at all. Not even a hunch?
你一点预感都没有
One of those interesting little hunches of yours?
没有
Nope. Not even a hunch.
我很意外  我非常肯定
I'm surprised, Mr. Keyes. I've formed a very definite opinion.
我知道狄先生
I think I know. In fact,
发生何事
I know I know what happened to Dietrichson.
你知道什么  这不是意外
You know you know what? I know it was not an accident.
你有何意见  我
What do you say to that? Me?
你即管说来听听
Well, you've got the ball. Let's see you run with it.
一个拥有敞大
There's a widespread feeling
办公室
that just because a man has a large office...
是  叫她进来
Yes? Have her come in, please.
一个拥有敞大办公室的人
There's a widespread feeling that...
一定是蠢材
just because a man has a large office, he must be an idiot.
我有访客  希望你们别介意
I'm having a visitor, if you don't mind.
不  我想你留下看我处理
No, no. I want you to stay and watch me handle this.
狄太太
Mrs. Dietrichson.
谢谢你前来  狄太太
Thank you very much for coming, Mrs. Dietrichson.
很感谢你  这位是祁先生
I assure you I appreciate it. This is Mr. Keyes.
你好你好
How do you do? How do you do?
还有黎先生  我见过黎先生  你好
And Mr. Neff. I've met Mr. Neff. How do you do?
狄太太  请坐
Mrs. Dietrichson. Won't you sit down?
请你节哀顺变
May I extend our sympathy in your bereavement?
我曾犹豫过
I hesitated before
是否应该现在叫你来
asking you to come here so soon after your loss.
但既然你来了
But now that you're here
希望你别介意
I hope you won't mind if I plunge straight into business?
你知道我们为何叫你来  是吗
You know why we asked you to come, don't you?
不  只知道你秘书说有急事
No. All I know is that your secretary made it sound very urgent.
你丈夫向本公司购买意外保险
Your husband had an accident policy with this company.
既然你不知道  狄太太
Evidently you don't know that, Mrs. Dietrichson.
对  曾在家里讨论
No. I remember some talk at the house,
但他不想买
but he didn't seem to want it.
你丈夫几天后购买了
Your husband took the policy out a few days later,
狄太太
Mrs. Dietrichson.
你可以在他私人物品中寻找
You'll probably find the policy among his personal effects.
他的保险箱还未开启
His safe-deposit box hasn't been opened yet.
听说要有税务专员在场
It seems a tax examiner has to be present.
对不起  狄太太
Please, Mrs. Dietrichson, I don't want you to think...
我不想你觉得受到盘问
you're being subjected to any questioning...
但我们想知道这件事
but there are a few things we should like to know.
什么事
What sort of things?
我们收到验尸官的报告
We have the report of the coroner's inquest.
意外死亡  我们并不满意
Accidental death. We are not entirely satisfied.
事实上  我们非常不满
In fact, we are not satisfied at all.
坦白说  我们怀疑
Frankly, Mrs. Dietrichson, we suspect...
他是自杀
a suicide.
对不起  你想喝水吗  好
I'm sorry. Would you like a glass of water? Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
你丈夫最近
Had your husband been depressed or moody lately,
是否情绪低落
Mrs. Dietrichson?
他有没有财政问题
Did he have financial worries, for instance?
他精神很好
He was perfectly all right
亦没有财政问题
and I don't know of any financial worries.
让我们研究一下这所谓的意外
Let us examine this so-called accident.
首先  你丈夫秘密地购买保险
First, your husband takes out
原因在何
this policy in absolute secrecy. Why?
因为他不想
Because he doesn't want his family
家人怀疑自己的用意
to suspect what he intends to do.
什么用意  接着  他独自出发
Do what? Next, he goes on this trip entirely alone.
他必须单独
He has to be alone.
他一路走到了望台
He hobbles all the way out to the observation platform.
他打了石膏
Very unlikely with his leg in a cast,
显然有特别原因
unless he has a very strong reason.
他到达后发现不只他一人  有个人
Once there, he finds he is not alone. There is a man there.
他叫什么名字  巴顿
What was his name, Keyes?
他叫谢杰逊  可能还在
His name was Jackson. Probably still is.
他骗说要雪茄盒
So he gets rid of this Jackson
而拜托谢杰逊
with some flimsy excuse about cigars.
他趁单独一人时做了  那件事  什么事
And then he is alone. And then he does it. Does what?
跳火车自杀  这事公司不受保
He jumps. Suicide. In which case, the company is not liable.
你应该知道  我们可以上法庭
You know that, of course. Now, we could go to court...
我一无所知  不知道为何来这里
I don't know anything. In fact, I don't know why I came here.
稍等一下
Just a moment, please.
我说可以上法庭  没说我们希望
I said we could go to court. I didn't say we want to.
我只是提议双方达成协议
What I want to suggest is a compromise on both sides.
协议金额  保单价值的一部分
A settlement for a certain sum, a part of the policy value.
算了吧  卢先生
Don't bother, Mr. Norton.
我进来前不知道你们欠我金钱
When I came in here, I had no idea you owed me any money.
你说你们欠钱  又说自己没有
You told me you did. Then you told me you didn't.
现在你说你想付一部分
Now you tell me you want to pay me a part of it, whatever it is.
你居然在这时间跟我讨价还价
You want to bargain with me, at a time like this.
我不喜欢你对我丈夫的看法
I don't like your insinuations about my husband,
以及你的手法
and I don't like your methods.
我亦不喜欢你  卢先生  再见  各位
In fact, I don't like you, Mr. Norton. Goodbye, gentlemen.
卢先生  你的确胸有成竹
Nice going, Mr. Norton. You sure carried that ball.
可惜笨手笨脚
Only you fumbled on the goal line.
你因为犯规
Then you heaved an illegal forward pass
而被判损失40码
and got thrown for a 40-yard loss.
你兵败如山倒
Now you can't pick yourself up
因为你站不住脚
because you haven't got a leg to stand on.
是吗  她可以上法庭
I haven't, eh? She can go to court
我们证明是自杀
and we can prove it was suicide.
可以吗
Oh, can we?
卢先生
Mr. Norton,
我起初也认为是自杀
the first thing that struck me was that suicide angle.
但我即使将这想法
Only I dumped it into the wastepaper basket
束之高阁
just three seconds later.
你间中要看看
You know, you ought to take a look
自杀的数据
at the statistics on suicide sometime.
也许会从中了解保险业
You might learn a little something about the insurance business.
祁先生  我在保险业长大
Mr. Keyes, I was raised in the insurance business.
对  在接待处
Yeah, in the front office.
你从没看过
Come now, you've never read an actuarial table
精算表吧
in your life, have you?
但我在自杀方面就有十册
Why, they've got 10 volumes on suicide alone.
种族肤色职业
Suicide by race, by color, by occupation...
姓名季节日历
by sex, by seasons of the year, by time of day.
自杀的方法
Suicide, how committed?
服毒  枪械  淹死  高处坠下
By poisons, by firearms, by drowning, by leaps.
服毒自杀又分成多类
Suicide by poison, subdivided by types of poison...
腐蚀  刺激  全身  气体
such as corrosive, irritant, systemic, gaseous, narcotic...
麻醉药  碱  蛋白之类
alkaloid, protein, and so forth.
高处坠下又分为跳楼
Suicide by leaps, subdivided by leaps from high places...
火车轮下  货车轮下  马蹄下
under the wheels of trains, under the wheels of trucks...
从蒸汽船坠下
under the feet of horses, from steamboats. But, Mr. Norton...
卢先生
of all the cases on record
根据过往案例
there's not one single case of suicide by leap...
没人曾从移动的火车尾部坠下
from the rear end of a moving train.
你知道尸体发现地点
And do you know how fast that train was going...
火车的时速是多少  每小时15英里
at the point where the body was found? 15 miles an hour.
在这慢速下
Now how can anybody jump off a slow moving train like that...
怎会有人认为能够自杀
with any kind of expectation that he would kill himself?
没有肥皂  卢先生
No. No soap, Mr. Norton.
我们今次
We're sunk, and we'll have to pay through the nose,
将会损失一笔
and you know it.
我可以喝吗
May I have this?
走吧  华达
Come on, Walter.
下次我会租礼服
Next time I'll rent a tuxedo.
对于你和你的数据
I could have hugged you right then and there, Keyes...
我当时真想拥抱你
you and your statistics.
你是我们唯一害怕的人
You were the only one we were really scared of...
但你却几乎成为我们的帮手
and instead you were almost playing on our team.
当晚回家时  我觉得轻松得多
That evening when I got home, my nerves had eased off.
我再次感到脚踏实地
I could feel the ground under my feet again.
看来前面将是一条坦途
And it looked like easy going from there on in.
我和菲莉几乎稳获那十万元
That $100,000 looked as safe for Phyllis and me...
好像支票已经存入银行
as if we had the check already deposited in the bank.
喂  嗨  宝贝  对  很好
Hello? Oh, hello, baby. Sure, everything is fine.
你表现很出色
You were wonderful in Norton's office.
感觉很怪  我一直想见你
I felt so funny, I wanted to look at you all the time.
你以为我不是吗  你在哪
How do you think I felt, baby? Where are you?
在杂货店  一街以外
At the drugstore. Just a block away.
我能上来吗  好  小心
Can I come up? Okay. But be careful.
不要让人看见
Don't let anybody see you.
嗨  巴顿
Hello, Keyes.
你有什么心事  那只断腿
What's on your mind? That broken leg.
那人的腿断了  你在说什么
The guy had a broken leg. What are you talking about?
狄先生  他买了意外保险
Talking about Dietrichson. He had accident insurance, didn't he?
对  然后他断了腿
Yeah. Then he broke his leg, didn't he?
那又怎样
So what? And he didn't put in a claim.
他没有索债  为什么呢  你想说什么
Why didn't he put in a claim? Why? What are you driving at?
我两小时吃晚餐  发现想不通
Walter, I had dinner two hours ago and it stuck half way.
那个隐形人又出来了
That little man of yours is acting up again, huh?
狄先生的案件不寻常
There's something wrong with the Dietrichson case.
为什么  因为他没索债
Why? Because he didn't file a claim?
也许他没有时间
Maybe he just didn't have time.
也许他不知道自己购买保险
Maybe he just didn't know that he was insured.
不  不可以
No. No, that couldn't be it.
你亲自送保单给他吗  是的
You delivered the policy to him personally, didn't you?
你收到他的支票
Yeah. You got his check?
当然
Sure I did.
还有没有苏打水  没有
Got any bicarbonate of soda? No, I haven't.
我跟这隐形人一起26年了
Walter, I've been living with this little man for 26 years.
他从没令我失望  这案件有问题
And he's never failed me yet. There's got to be something wrong.
也许卢敦说得对  不是自杀
Well, maybe Norton was right. Maybe it was suicide.
不是自杀
No. Not suicide.
但也不是意外  那是什么
But not an accident, either. What else?
听好  华达
Now look, Walter.
有人购买了一份
A guy takes out an accident policy that's worth $100,000...
若死于火车会获赔十万元的保险
if he's killed on a train.
两周后  他的确死于火车
Then two weeks later, he is killed on a train.
但不是火车意外
And not in a train accident, mind you,
而是从了望台调下来
but falling off some silly observation car.
你知道这个几率有多高
Do you know what the mathematical probability of that is?
大约几十亿分之一
One out of I don't know how many billions.
那人还是断腿的
And add to that the broken leg.
不会是这样的
No, it just can't be the way it looks.
事有蹊跷  例如什么
Something has been worked on us. Such as what?
谋杀
Murder?
你有没有薄荷
Don't you have any peppermint or something?
对不起  要苏打水  不用了
Sorry. Want a little soda water? No, no, no.
你怀疑谁
Who do you suspect?
我喜欢为自己行个方便
Maybe I like to make things easy for myself.
但我倾向怀疑受益人
But I always tend to suspect the beneficiary.
你是指他妻子
You mean the wife? Yeah.
对
That wide-eyed dame
一无所知的大眼太太
that just didn't know anything about anything.
你傻了  她不在火车上
You're crazy, Keyes. She wasn't even on the train.
我知道
I know she wasn't, Walter.
我没说自己知道事情经过
I don't claim to know how it was worked, or who worked it...
但我知道事情的确发生了
but all I know is that it was worked.
我要去杂货店
I've got to get to a drugstore.
这东西就像心头大石
This thing feels like a hunk of concrete inside me.
晚安  华达晚安  巴顿
Good night, Walter. Good night, Keyes.
明早在公司见好
See you at the office in the morning. Yeah.
若不是卢敦和他的公司政策
I'd like to move in on her right now, tonight.
我今晚就打算
If it wasn't for Norton and his striped-pants ideas
对付她
about company policy...
我会派警察监视  令她晕头转向
I'd have the police after her so fast it'd make her head spin.
他们会将她放在榨汁机
They'd put her through the wringer...
你知道会得到什么
and, brother, the things they would squeeze out.
但你没有证据追查
Only you haven't got a single thing to go on, Keyes.
不多  只有26年经验
Not too much. Just 26 years experience...
及数据资料
all the percentage there is,
以及心头这块大石
and this hunk of concrete in my stomach.
可以给我一点火
Can I have one of those things?
再见  巴顿  再见  华达
Good night, Keyes. So long, Walter.
他知道多少  他什么也不知道
How much does he know? He doesn't know anything.
只有预感
It's those stinking hunches of his.
但他无法证明什么吧
And he can't prove anything, can he?
只要我们小心  我们暂时不能见面
Not if we're careful. Not if we don't see each other for a while.
多久  直至事情淡化
How long a while? Until this dies down.
你不了解巴顿
You don't know Keyes.
他一咬住就不会放开
Once he gets his teeth into something, he never lets go.
他会调查你  紧盯着你
He'll investigate you, have you shadowed.
他会从现在起盯着你
He'll watch you every minute from now on.
你害怕吗  宝贝  我很害怕
You afraid, baby? Yes, I'm afraid.
不是害怕巴顿  而是害怕我们
But not of Keyes. I'm afraid of us.
我们的关系已经变了
We're not the same anymore.
我们是为了一起而这样做
We did it so we could be together,
但这却令我们分开
but instead of that it's pulling us apart.
不是吗  你在说什么
Isn't it, Walter? What are you talking about?
你不再在乎我们能否再见
And you don't really care whether we see each other or not.
别这样说  宝贝
Shut up, baby.
太平保险  午安
Pacific All Risk. Good afternoon.
你好  黎先生
Hello, Mr. Neff.
你好  我是狄露娜
Hello. Lola Dietrichson.
你不记得我吗  当然记得
Don't you remember me? Yes. Yes, of course.
我能跟你谈一下吗
Could I talk with you just a few minutes?
有没有地方可以单独谈
Somewhere where we could be alone?
有  来我的办公室
Oh, yes. Come into my office.
发生了什么事吗
Is it something about what happened?
是  关于我父亲的死
Yes, Mr. Neff. It's about my father's death.
我很难过  狄小姐
I'm terribly sorry, Miss Dietrichson.
我可以单独用办公室一会吗
Lou, do you mind if I use the office alone for a few minutes?
没问题  华达
No. It's all yours, Walter.
看我  黎先生
Look at me, Mr. Neff.
我不是神经失常  亦没有哭
I'm not crazy. I'm not hysterical. I'm not even crying.
但我觉得整件事有很大问题
But I have the awful feeling that something is wrong...
我尝过这种感觉...当我母亲死去
and I had that same feeling once before, when my mother died.
你母亲何时死去
When your mother died?
我们住在箭头湖  六年前的事
We were at Lake Arrowhead. That was six years ago.
我们在那有小屋
We had a cabin there.
我母亲因为肺炎
It was winter and very cold.
病得很重
My mother was very sick with pneumonia.
她有一名护士
She had a nurse with her.
小屋里有我们三人
There were just the three of us in the cabin.
有一晚我起床走到母亲的房间
One night I got up and went into my mother's room.
她发高烧  说话迷糊
She was delirious with fever.
被铺全在地上
All the bed covers were on the floor
窗户大开
and the windows were wide open.
护士不在房间
The nurse wasn't in the room.
我尽快替母亲盖上被铺
I ran and covered my mother up as quickly as I could.
此时我听见门口打开
Just then I heard a door open behind me.
护士站在那里
The nurse stood there.
她默不作声  但她的眼神
She didn't say a word, but there was a look in her eyes...
令我无法忘记
I'll never forget.
两天后我母亲死去
Two days later, my mother was dead.
你知道那护士是谁
Do you know who that nurse was?
谁  菲莉
No. Who? Phyllis.
我试图跟爸爸说  但是我只是小孩
I tried to tell my father, but I was just a kid then.
他不相信我  半年后  她就嫁给他
He wouldn't listen to me. Six months later she married him...
我一直安慰自己说
and I kind of talked myself out of the idea
她不会这样做
she could have done anything like that.
但这种感觉回来了
But now it's all back again,
我父亲也死去
now that something's happened to my father, too.
不要胡言乱语
You're not making sense, Miss Dietrichson.
你爸是从火车掉下
Your father fell off a train.
对  事发两天前
Yes, and two days before he fell off that train,
菲莉做了一件事
what was Phyllis doing?
她在房间对着镜子
She was in her room in front of a mirror, with a black hat on...
戴着黑帽  披着黑纱
pinning a black veil to it.
急不及待想看看悼念的外表
As if she couldn't wait to see how she would look in mourning.
你一定是受惊  狄小姐
You've had a pretty bad shock, Miss Dietrichson.
那些事是你想象出来的吗
Aren't you just imagining these things?
我望着她在镜子里的眼神
I caught her eyes in the mirror.
跟母亲死去前一模一样
They had that look in them they had before my mother died.
一模一样
That same look.
你不喜欢继母  是吗
You don't like your stepmother, do you?
因为她不是亲生母亲
Isn't it just because she is your stepmother?
我憎死她  是她做的  她为了钱而这样做
I loathe her because she did it. She did it for the money.
但你不会赔钱给她吧
Only you're not going to pay her, are you, Mr. Neff?
她今次不会逍遥法外
She's not going to get away with it this time,
我会揭发她
because I'm going to speak up.
我要将我知道的告诉大家
I'm going to tell everything I know.
你要小心说话
You'd better be careful, saying things like...
我不害怕  你会明白
I'm not afraid. You'll see.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我无意的
I didn't mean to act like this.
你还跟谁说起这些事
All this that you've been telling me, who else have you told?
没有
No one.
你的继母呢  当然没有
How about your stepmother? Of course not.
我搬走了
I've moved out.
不再住那里
I'm not living at home anymore.
你没跟你男朋友尼诺说过吧
And you haven't told that boyfriend of yours? Zachetti?
我没有见他  我们吵架了
I'm not seeing him anymore. We had a fight.
你住在哪里
Where are you living now?
好莱坞的小公寓
I got myself a little apartment in Hollywood.
四面墙壁  你坐着看墙壁
Four walls, and you just sit and look at them?
是  黎先生
Yes, Mr. Neff.
那天晚上我带她到奥维拿街
So that evening I took her to dinner...
一间偏僻的
at a Mexican restaurant down on
墨西哥餐厅
Olvera Street where nobody would see us.
我想逗她开心
I wanted to cheer her up.
翌日是星期日  我们驾车去沙滩
The next day was Sunday and we went for a ride down to the beach.
她心情好了一点  甚至会笑
She had loosened up a bit, she was even laughing.
我要确保她
I had to make sure that
不会透漏菲莉的事
she wouldn't tell that stuff about Phyllis to anybody else.
无论真伪  那将会是计时炸弹
It was dynamite, whether it was true or not.
我亦没有机会告诉菲莉
And I had no chance to talk to Phyllis.
你象一只鹰般盯着她
You were watching her like a hawk, Keyes.
我不能打给她
I couldn't even phone her
因为我担心你会监听
because I was afraid you had the wires tapped.
星期一早上我桌上
Monday morning there was a note on my desk
有字条说你想见我
that you wanted to see me, Keyes.
我曾经想过会否是露娜
For a minute I wondered if it could be about Lola.
原来更糟糕
It was worse.
你门外是我最不想见到的人
Outside your door was the last guy in the world I wanted to see.
进来  华达
Come in. Come in, Walter.
嗨  巴顿  我想问你
Hello, Keyes. I want to ask you something.
我们认识多年
After all the years we've known each other...
介意我直言不讳吗
do you mind if I make a rather blunt statement?
关于什么  我
About what? About me.
我是一个伟人对
Walter, I'm a very great man. Yeah?
狄氏案是谋杀
This Dietrichson business, it's murder...
谋杀始终会露出马脚
and murders don't come any neater.
一个毕生难逢的周  密谋杀
As fancy a piece of homicide as anybody ever ran into...
聪明决定  几乎完美  只是
smart, tricky, almost perfect, but...
我已经全部想通
I think Papa has it all figured out.
用薄纸包裹
Figured out and wrapped up in tissue paper
再加粉红色蝴蝶结
with pink ribbons on it.
继续说  我在听
Go ahead. I'm listening. You know what?
告诉你  姓狄的家伙没上过火车
That guy Dietrichson was never on the train.
他没有  是的
He wasn't? No, he wasn't.
在时速15英里的火车上
Now look, Walter. You can't be sure of killing a man...
将受害人抛下  未必能杀死他
by throwing him off a train that's going 15 miles an hour.
唯一办法是先杀死他
The only way you can be sure is to kill him first...
再将尸体丢在路轨
and then throw his body on the tracks.
那代表在火车上杀死他
Now that would mean either killing him on the train...
或者
or, and this is where it really gets fancy,
在别处杀了她
you kill him somewhere else...
然后将他放在路轨
and put him on the tracks.
两个可能性  我相信第二个
Two possibilities, and I personally buy the second.
我想也没想过
You're way ahead of me, Keyes.
事情是这样的
Well, look, Walter, it was like this.
他们杀死那家伙...妻子和某人
They killed the guy, the wife and a somebody else...
有人拿起拐杖
and the somebody else took the crutches
假扮狄先生上车
and went on the train as Dietrichson...
然后那人跳车
then the somebody else jumped off...
再将尸体放在路轨
then they put the body on the tracks where the train had passed.
假冒死者  易如反掌
An impersonation, see? A cinch to work.
因为当时是夜晚  很少问人
Because it was night, very few people were about...
他们忙着留意拐杖
they have the crutches to stare at...
反而留意不到那人
they never really looked at the man at all.
很有趣  但有点过分有趣
Fancy all right, Keyes, but maybe it's a little too fancy.
是吗  线索终于能够拼合
Is it? I tell you, it all fits together like a watch.
看看我们有何办法证明
Now let's see what we have in the way of proof.
曾经仔细留意
The only guy who really got a good look
冒充狄先生的人
at this supposed Dietrichson...
坐在我办公室外面
is sitting right outside my office.
我请他从俄勒冈来
I took the trouble to bring him down here from Oregon.
进来  谢先生  好的
Come here, Mr. Jackson. Yes, sir, Mr. Keyes.
你的雪茄不错
These are fine cigars you smoke.
价钱不贵真好
Two for a quarter. That's what I said.
你看过照片吗
Well, did you study those photographs?
是  我非常仔细看过
Yes, indeed. I studied them thoroughly.
你想清楚了吗
Very thoroughly. Have you made up your mind?
祁先生  我是美德福人
Mister Keyes, I'm a Medford man. Medford, Oregon.
美德福人一向需要时间想清楚
Up in Medford we take our time making up our mind.
这里不是美德福  事情很紧急  事不宜迟
Well, we're not in Medford now. We're in a hurry. Let's have it.
这些是狄先生的照片
Are these photographs of the late Mr. Dietrichson?
是
Yes.
那我肯定不是  什么意思
Then my answer is no. What do you mean, no?
我是指火车上的人不是他
I mean, this is not the man that was on the train.
你愿意发誓吗
Will you swear to that?
我是美德福人
Mr. Keyes, I'm a Medford man. Medford, Oregon.
一言九鼎  我愿意发誓
If I say it, I mean it. If I mean it, of course I'll swear it.
听见了  华达  这就是证据
There you are, Walter. There's your proof.
这位是黎先生  我们的营业员
This is Mr. Neff, one of our salesmen.
幸会  黎先生你好吗
Pleased to meet you, Mr. Neff. Pleased, indeed.
很好  有心
How are you? Very fine, thank you.
请坐  谢先生
Never was better. Sit down, Mr. Jackson.
可以形容一下
Just how would you describe
瞭望台的男人
the man you saw on the observation platform?
我肯定他比较年轻
Well, I'm pretty sure he was a younger man...
比照片中人年轻10至15年
about 10 or 15 years younger than the man in these photographs.
狄先生大约50岁吗  华达
Dietrichson was about 50, wasn't he, Walter?
保单上是51岁
Fifty-one, according to the policy.
我看见的人绝对不像是51岁
The man I saw was nothing like 51 years old.
当晚了望台很昏暗
Of course, it was pretty dark out on that platform.
现在回想  他刻意背对着我
Come to think of it, he tried to keep his back towards me.
但我非常肯定谢谢你
But I'm positive just the same. Thank you, Jackson.
你明白此事必须绝对保  密
Of course, you understand this matter is strictly confidential?
若上法庭
We may need you again down here in Los Angeles,
我们需要你去洛杉矶
if the case comes to court.
我愿意为你效劳
Any time you need me, I'm entirely at your disposal, gentlemen.
只要费用由你支付  当然
Expenses paid, of course. Oh, yes. Yes. Of course.
替我找支帐部的鲁宾
Get me Lubin, in the cashier's office.
喂  鲁宾  我是巴顿
Hello, Lubin. This is Keyes.
我现在叫谢先生下来
Listen. I'm sending a man named Jackson down to you
收取费用
with an expense account.
他为
Well, we brought him down here from Medford,
狄氏案
Oregon in connection with...
从美德福而来
the Dietrichson claim.
你帮我支付他的酒店费用
Well, take care of his hotel bill, will you?
你去过俄勒冈吗
Ever been in Oregon, Mr. Neff?
是的  他马上来
Yeah. He'll be right down.
没有  从没去过
No. Never been up there.
等等  你会去垂钓吗
Wait a minute. You go trout fishing?
我也许在加玛夫瀑布见过你  没有  我不钓鱼
Maybe I saw you up Klamath Falls way. Nope. I don't fish.
你不钓鱼  黎先生
You don't go fishing, Mr. Neff. Neff. It's the name.
我记得了  在科瓦利斯的黎氏  我跟他们没关系
There's a family of Neffs in Corvallis. No relation.
那个姓黎的是汽车经纪
Let me see. This man's an automobile dealer in Corvallis.
听说很德高望重
A very reputable man, too, I'm told. All right, Mr. Jackson.
谢先生  你可以去支帐部
Suppose you go down to the cashier's office.
11楼27室
Room 27 on the 11th floor.
他们会支付费用
He'll take care of your expense account
及今晚火车票
and your ticket for the train tonight.
今晚
Tonight?
明天早上
Tomorrow morning would suit me better.
会比较好
There's a very good osteopath in town...
我想去看城里的著名整骨医生  整骨医生
I'd like to see before I leave. Osteopath?
不要将费用计算在内
Well, just don't put her on the expense account.
再见
Well, goodbye, gentlemen.
幸会再见
It's been a pleasure. Goodbye.
太好了  华达
There it is, Walter.
纸快包不住火了
It's beginning to come apart at the seams already.
谋杀永远不会完美  迟早揭发
Murder's never perfect. Always comes apart sooner or later.
若有两人参与  就更快东窗事发
And when two people are involved, it's usually sooner.
现在知道狄太太和某人参与
Now, we know the Dietrichson dame is in it, and a somebody else.
不久就会知道某人是谁
Pretty soon we'll know who that somebody else is.
他一定会出现
He'll show. He's got to show.
他们总要在某时某刻见面
Sometime, somewhere, they've got to meet.
两人阵脚大乱
Their emotions are all kicked up.
是爱是恨并不重要
Whether it's love or hate doesn't matter.
他们始终无法不接触对方
They can't keep away from each other.
他们以为两人参与是双倍安全
They may think it's twice as safe because there are two of them.
其实不是双倍安全
But it isn't twice as safe.
而是二十倍危险  他们犯下谋杀罪
It's 10 times twice as dangerous. They've committed a murder...
这不像坐火车
and it's not like taking a trolley ride together...
可以在不同站下车
where they can get off at different stops.
他们会被困在一起
They're stuck with each other and they've got to ride...
直至终点
all the way to the end of the line.
这是单程车  终站是坟墓
And it's a one-way trip, and the last stop is the cemetery.
她已经申请索偿
She put in her claim.
我将会还击
I'm gonna throw it right back at her.
她即管控告我  我已准备迎战
Let her sue us if she dares.
她和某人
I'll be ready for her and that somebody else.
他们会一起自掘坟墓
They'll be digging their own graves.
狄太太  这里是杰利店打来
Mrs. Dietrichson? This is Jerry's Market.
我们收到你要的
We just got in a shipment of that English soap
英国肥皂
you were asking about.
你今天能来取吗  谢谢  狄太太
Will you be coming by today? Thank you, Mrs. Dietrichson.
嗨  华达过来
Hello, Walter. Come over here.
什么事  大事不妙
What's the matter? Everything's the matter.
巴顿会拒绝你索债
Keyes is rejecting your claim.
他虎视眈眈着
He's sitting back with his mouth watering,
等待你提出控告
waiting for you to sue.
他想你控告  但你不可以
He wants you to sue, but you're not going to.
他凭什么阻止我  他理直气壮
What's he got to stop me? He's got plenty.
他知道事件如何发生
He's figured out how it was worked.
知道火车上是另有其人
He knows it was somebody else on the train...
还找到一个可以作证的目击者
and he's dug up a witness he thinks can prove it.
证明什么  若他拒绝  我就控告
Prove it how? If he rejects that claim, I have to sue.
是吗  告上法庭后
Yeah? And then you're in court
就会是非不断
and a lot of other things are going to come up.
例如关于你和首任狄太太
Like, for instance, about you and the first Mrs. Dietrichson.
我和首任狄太太怎么了
What about me and the first Mrs. Dietrichson?
她的死去经过  还有你戴黑帽
The way she died.
在你需要
And about that black hat you were trying on
黑帽之前
before you needed a black hat.
露娜跟你说那些天花乱坠的故事
Lola's been telling you some of her cockeyed stories.
她一直在晃你  坦白说  是我一直见她
She's been seeing you. I've been seeing her, if you want to know.
令她不会说出她知道的事情
So she won't yell her head off about what she knows.
她只是在你面前
She's putting on an act for you,
假哭搏同情
crying all over your shoulder, the lying...
不要扯她
Keep her out of this.
下水
All I'm telling you is we're not going to sue.
因为你嫌钱腥
Because you don't want the money anymore...
不想要钱
even if you could have it, because she's...
她突然令你觉得惊为天人
made you feel like a heel all of a sudden?
已经与钱无关
It isn't the money anymore.
性命攸关
It's our necks. We're pulling out, do you understand?
因为那祁巴顿  你别骗我
Because of what Keyes can do? You're not fooling me, Walter.
是因为露娜  你对她父亲所做的
It's because of Lola, what you did to her father.
你害怕她
You're afraid she
终有一天会发现
might find out someday and you can't take it, can you?
我说不要扯她下水
I said, leave her out of this.
我说的是我
It's me I'm talking about.
我不想你丢下我  别再说
I don't want to be left out of it. Stop saying that.
事情未能如我们所愿
It's just that it hasn't worked as we wanted.
我们无法脱身
We can't go through with it, that's all.
我们已经脱身
We have gone through with it.
艰难时期已过
The tough part is all behind us.
只要镇定  不要软化
We just have to hold on now and not go soft inside...
象开始时齐心合力
stick close together the way we started out.
小心
Watch it.
我爱你  华达  我恨你
I loved you, Walter, and I hated him.
但我遇上你前从没想过这样做
But I wasn't going to do anything about it, not until I met you.
是你一手计划  我只想他死去
You planned the whole thing. I only wanted him dead.
我就是亲手害死他的人
And I'm the one that fixed it so he was dead.
你是这个意思吗  没人可以退出
Is that what you're telling me? And nobody's pulling out.
我们要一起开始  一起结束
We went into this together, we're coming out at the end together.
大家都要彻头彻尾  你要记住
It's straight down the line for both of us, remember?
对  我记得
Yes, I remembered.
就如我记得你所说  巴顿
Just like I remembered what you had told me, Keyes...
关于坐车
about that trolley car ride...
一定要在终站下车
and how there was no getting off till the end of the line...
终站是坟墓
where the cemetery was.
然后我想到坟墓是给谁的
And then I got to thinking what cemeteries are for.
是用来给死人的
They're to put dead people in.
那是我第一次
I guess that was the first time
这样想起菲莉
I ever thought about Phyllis that way.
死亡
Dead, I mean.
若她死了会怎样
And how it would be if she were dead.
我那星期见过露娜三四次
I saw Lola three or four times that week.
有一晚我跟她到好莱坞露天剧场
One night we went up into the hills behind the Hollywood Bowl.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
I guess it sounds crazy, Keyes, but it was only with her that...
但是跟她在一起  我才能够放松
I could relax and let go a little.
你为什么哭
Why are you crying?
有事跟我说
Not gonna tell me, huh?
当然会告诉你  我只会跟你说
Of course I will, Walter. I wouldn't tell anybody else but you.
是尼诺  他怎么了
It's about Nino. Zachetti? What about him?
他们合谋杀死我父亲  他和菲莉
They killed my father together. He and Phyllis.
他是帮凶  我知道
He helped her do it. I know he did.
你为什么这样说
What makes you say that?
我跟踪他
I've been following him.
他每晚逗去家里找她
He's been to her house, night after night.
一直以来菲莉都和他一起
It was Phyllis and him all along.
也许他只是骗我
Maybe he was just going with me as a blind.
谋杀当晚
And the night of the murder...
你答应不会向别人透漏
You promised me you weren't gonna talk like this anymore.
他应该在加州大学讲座后来找我
He was supposed to pick me up after a lecture at UCLA.
但他爽约  他说他病了
But he never showed up. He said he was sick.
病了
Sick!
他不能出现
He couldn't show up,
因为我爸在火车上
because the train was leaving with my father on it.
也许我想得太多  想傻了
Maybe I'm just crazy. Maybe it's all in my mind.
对  你想得太多
Sure, it's all in your mind.
希望是这样  因为我爱他
I only wish it were, Walter, 'cause I still love him.
尼诺  菲莉与尼诺
Zachetti. Phyllis and Zachetti.
他去她家里做什么
What was he doing up at her house?
我想不通
I couldn't figure that one out.
我尝试思索  却苦无结果
I tried to make sense out of it and got nowhere.
但真正的思索在翌日出现
But the real braintwister came the next day.
巴顿
You sprang it on me, Keyes,
当你在放办公时间后
after office hours, when you caught me...
在大堂叫我时发生的
down in the lobby of the building.
华达  等一下
Walter. Walter, just a minute.
嗨  巴顿  听好了  华达
Hello, Keyes. Just hang on to your hat, Walter.
什么事  没什么
What for? Oh, nothing much.
狄氏案终于真相大白
That Dietrichson case just busted wide open.
怎么说  那家伙出现了
How do you mean? The guy showed. That's how.
什么家伙  协助她的家伙
What guy? The guy who helped her do it.
另一个人
The somebody else?
真的吗  对  她刚入庭控告我们
No kidding? Yeah. She just filed suit against us.
我已准备好了
It's okay by me.
上法庭时
When we get them in that courtroom,
我会迎头痛击他俩
I'll tear them to pieces, both of them.
来  我请你喝马天尼  不  谢了
Come on. I'll buy you a martini, Walter. No thanks, Keyes.
加两片橄榄叶
With two olives.
不  我约了人  要剃须擦鞋
No, I've got to get a shave and a shoeshine. I've got a date.
玛琪  大概还是用瓶子喝酒
Margie. I still bet she drinks from the bottle.
你买雪茄  售货员会给你火柴
They give you matches when you buy cigars, you know.
你只需要开口问
All you have to do is ask for them.
我不喜欢
Don't like them,
总是在我口袋爆炸  再见  华达
they always explode in my pocket. So long, Walter.
我害怕得发抖
I was scared stiff, Keyes.
也许你在跟我玩猫捉老鼠
Maybe you were playing cat-and-mouse with me.
也许你一直知道我就是同谋
Maybe you knew all along I was the somebody else.
我知道答案在哪里  你的办公室
I had to find out, and I knew where to look. In your office.
致卢敦先生的备忘录
Memo to Mr. Norton.
机  密  狄氏案
Confidential. Dietrichson file.
关于你提议
With regard to your proposal to
监视黎华达
put Walter Neff under surveillance...
我对此极为反对
I disagree absolutely.
我已调查过他在案发当晚的行踪
I have investigated his movements on the night of the crime...
他从下午7时至15时一直在寓所
and he's definitely placed in his apartment from 7:15 p.m. On.
况且  我与华达是11年的深交
In addition to this, I have known Neff intimately for 11 years...
我愿意担保他的人格  毫无保留
and I personally vouch for him without reservation.
况且  黎华达
Furthermore, no connection whatsoever has been established...
与狄太太没有关联
between Walter Neff and Mrs. Phyllis Dietrichson...
但我现在
whereas I am now able to report
可以指出
that such a connection has been established...
她和另一位男子有关联
between her and another man.
这人曾被目睹在7月9  10  11
This man has been observed to visit Mrs. Dietrichson...
12  13日多次探访狄太太
on the nights of July 9th, 10th, 11th, 12th and 13th.
我们成功认出该人是卓尼诺
We have succeeded in identifying him as one Nino Zachetti...
28岁的前医科学生
former medical student, age of 28...
住在拉布利亚南街
residing at Lilac Court Apartments...
紫香阁1228号
12281/2 North La Brea Avenue.
我们调查过卓尼诺  在案发当晚的行踪
We have checked Zachetti's movements on the night of the crime...
发现他没有不在场证据
and have found that they cannot be accounted for.
我正准备一份详细报告给你参详
I am preparing a more detailed report for your consideration.
我深信我们已经
It is my belief that
有足够证据
we already have sufficient evidence against Zachetti...
让警察向尼诺及狄太太采取行动
and Mrs. Dietrichson to justify police action.
我强烈要求
I strongly urge
将个案
that this whole matter be turned over to the office...
交给检查处
of the district attorney.
祁巴顿敬上
Respectfully, Barton Keyes.
菲莉  我是华达  我非见你不可  今晚
Phyllis? It's Walter. I've got to see you. Tonight.
是  一定要今晚
Yes, it has to be tonight.
11时如何
How's 11:00?
不用担心巴顿
Don't worry about Keyes.
前门不要锁上  把灯关掉就行
Just leave the front door unlocked and put the lights out.
不  没人再监视房子
No, nobody's watching the house. Not anymore.
只是不想邻居看见  我说过不用担心巴顿
It's just for the neighbors. I told you not to worry about Keyes.
今晚11时见
I'll see you at 11:00. Yeah.
好  再见  宝贝
Goodbye, baby.
我大概
I guess I don't have to tell you...
不用跟你说我的企图
what I intended to do at 11:00, Keyes.
我第一次看见
For the first time,
自己处于什么困局
I saw a way to get clear of the whole mess I was in...
还有菲莉的困局
and of Phyllis, too, all at the same time.
对  那是我的想法
Yeah, that's what I thought.
但我没想到她另有计划
What I didn't know was that she had plans of her own.
进来  华达
In here, Walter.
嗨  宝贝
Hello, baby.
有其他人在吗  没有  怎么了
Anybody else in the house? Nobody. Why?
什么音乐  街外的收音机
What's that music? A radio up the street.
跟我初次来的情况一样
Just like the first time I came here, isn't it?
我们在谈汽车保险
We were talking about automobile insurance.
但你只想到谋财害命
Only you were thinking about murder.
我只想到脚镯
I was thinking about that anklet.
你现在想什么
And what are you thinking about now?
我已经想清楚
I'm all through thinking, baby.
我只是来道别  道别
I just came to say goodbye. Goodbye?
你去哪里  你继续玩游戏  我不玩了
Where are you going? You're the one that's going, baby. Not me.
我现在就要下车
I'm getting off the trolley car right at this corner.
不要拐弯抹角  有话直接说
Suppose you stop being fancy. Let's have it, whatever it is.
好  我告诉你  我朋友作出一个有趣理论
All right, I'll tell you. A friend of mine's got a funny theory.
他说当两个人
He says when two people commit a murder,
犯下谋杀案
it's sort of like they're riding...
就好像两人一起坐车
on a trolley car together. One can't get off without the other.
两人被困在一起
They're stuck with each other and they have to go on...
直至终站才能下车
riding together clear to the end of the line.
而终站就是坟墓
And the last stop is the cemetery.
也许他有线索  说得对
Maybe he's got something there. You bet he has.
两人要到终站才能下车
Two people are gonna ride to the end of the line, all right.
但我不会是其中一人
Only I'm not gonna be one of them.
我找到另一个人替我完成旅程
I've got another guy to finish my ride for me.
你在说谁  你的朋友
Just who are you talking about? An acquaintance of yours.
卓先生
A Mr. Zachetti.
我参与此事
Come on, baby, I just got into this thing...
只因为
because I happen to know
我了解保险
a little something about insurance, didn't I?
我是个无用的人
I was a sucker.
你一收到钱
I'd have been brushed off
就会甩掉我
just as soon as you got your hands on the money.
没人会甩掉你  省口气吧  让我告诉你
Nobody wanted to brush you off. Save it. I'm telling this.
你一直与卓你尼诺合谋  是吗
It's been you and that Zachetti guy all along, hasn't it?
不是
That's not true.
无论如何  分别都不大了
Doesn't make any difference if it's true or not.
巴顿相信他要找的人
The point is, Keyes believes Zachetti is
是卓尼诺
the one he's been looking for.
卓尼诺不用多久
He'll have him in that gas chamber
就会被判死刑
before he knows what's happened to him.
我怎么了  别傻了
What's happening to me all this time? Don't be silly, baby.
你以为呢
What do you think is gonna happen to you?
你是他的帮凶  不是吗
You helped him do the murder, didn't you?
那是祁巴顿的想法
That's what Keyes thinks.
既然如此  我就来个顺水推舟
And what's good enough for Keyes is good enough for me.
我不同意
Maybe it's not good enough for me, Walter.
这个做法
Maybe I don't go for the idea.
我宁愿一走了之
Maybe I'd rather talk.
有时人会穷途末路
Sometimes people are where they can't talk.
甚至被埋在泥土
Under six feet of dirt, maybe.
若那是你
And if it was you,
他们会控告尼诺
they'd charge that up to Zachetti, too, wouldn't they?
他们一定会  那是自然的事
Sure they would, and that's just what's gonna happen, baby.
因为他今晚会来  大约15分钟后
'Cause he's coming here tonight, in about 15 minutes.
警察已监视他  一切已成定局
With the cops right behind him. It's all taken care of.
你可以逍遥法外  是吗
That would make everything lovely for you, wouldn't it?
是  这将会在
Right. And it's got to be done
你的追求者接受审讯
before that suit of yours comes to trial...
以及露娜有机会说话值钱
and Lola gets a chance to sound off...
让你没机会
before they trip you up on the stand,
揭发我
and you start to go in drag me down with you.
也许我叫尼诺来
Maybe I had Zachetti here
没人能控告我
so they won't get a chance to trip me up...
我们可以拿钱  相宿相栖
so we can get the money and be together.
说得真动听
That's cute. Say it again.
他过来问我露娜在何处
He came here first to ask where Lola was.
我叫他回来  欺骗他
I made him come back. I was working on him.
他是那种冲动的急性子
He's a crazy sort of guy, quick-tempered.
我不断向他骗说她另结新欢
I kept hammering into him that she was with another man...
让他怒不可遏
so he'd go into one of his jealous rages,
再去找她
and then I'd tell him where she was.
你知道他会做出什么事  对吧
And you know what he would've done to her, don't you, Walter?
对  我今次相信你
Yeah, and for once I believe you,
因为够卑鄙
because it's just rotten enough.
我们一样卑鄙
We're both rotten.
但你比我更卑鄙
Only you're a little more rotten.
你骗我去谋杀你的丈夫
You got me to take care of your husband for you...
然后让尼诺杀死露娜
and then you got Zachetti to take care of Lola,
甚至我
maybe take care of me, too.
再找人
Then somebody else would have come along
对付尼诺
to take care of Zachetti for you.
是不是这样  假如是呢
That's the way you operate, isn't it, baby? Suppose it is.
你有其他想法吗
Is what you've got cooked up for tonight any better?
我不再喜欢这种音乐  介意我关掉窗户吗
I don't like that music anymore. Mind if I close the window?
你应该可以打得更准
You can do better than that, can't you, baby?
最好再试试
Better try it again.
也许我应该走近一点
Maybe if I came a little closer?
现在怎样  你可以下手吗
How's this? Think you can do it now?
你怎么不再打一枪
Why didn't you shoot again, baby?
别说你
Don't tell me
一直爱我
it's because you've been in love with me all this time.
不  我从没爱过你  不单止你  所有人都是
No, I never loved you, Walter, not you or anybody else.
我是卑鄙无耻的人  利用你
I'm rotten to the heart. I used you, just as you said.
你只是我的工具
That's all you ever meant to me...
直至刚才
until a minute ago...
当我发现自己无法打第二枪
when I couldn't fire that second shot.
我从没想过会爱上一个人
I never thought that could happen to me.
对不起  我不相信你  我不是求你相信
Sorry, baby. I'm not buying. I'm not asking you to buy.
抱着我
Just hold me close.
再见  宝贝
Goodbye, baby.
尼诺
Zachetti.
过来
Come here.
我叫你过来
I said, come here.
我是黎华达  是吗  我不喜欢你
My name is Neff. Yeah, and I still don't like it.
什么事
What do you want?
听着  孩子
Look, kid.
我想送东西给你  一个五分币
I want to give you a present. This nice new nickel.
你在玩什么
What's the gag? Suppose you go on back down the hill...
你回山下的杂货店打个电话
to the drugstore and make a phone call.
留着这硬币  自己买雪糕筒
Keep your nickel and buy yourself an ice-cream cone.
电话是G0386
The number is Granite-0-3-8-6.
找名叫露娜的狄小姐
Ask for Miss Dietrichson. First name is Lola.
她一文不值
She isn't worth a nickel.
若要我跟她谈  一定不会用电话
If I ever talk to her, it's not going to be over any telephone.
你自以为了不起
Tough, aren't you?
拿着钱去打给她  她想你找她
Here, take the nickel and call her. She wants you to.
她不想要我
She doesn't want any part of me.
我知道有人这样说  那不是真的
I know who told you that. It's not true.
露娜一直爱你
Lola's in love with you. She always has been.
不要问我原因  我也不明白
Don't ask me why. I couldn't even guess.
拿着  G0386  快打给她
Here. Granite-0-3-8-6. Now go on and call her.
走吧  那边
Go on. That way.
现在差不多四时半
It's almost 4:30 now, Keyes.
天气很冷
It's cold.
我在想她是否仍然独自躺在家里
I wonder if she's still lying alone up there in that house...
抑或警方已经发现她
or if they've found her by now.
我千头万绪  但已不再重要
I wonder a lot of things. They don't matter anymore.
但我想你帮我一个忙
Except I want you to do a favor for me, Keyes.
我想你在东窗事发前
I want you to be the one to tell Lola,
告诉露娜
kind of gently, before it breaks wide open.
我想你照顾她和卓尼诺
And I want you to take care of her and that guy Zachetti...
让他不用受太多苦难
so he doesn't get pushed around too much.
嗨  巴顿
Hello, Keyes.
你今天很早起床
Up pretty early, aren't you?
我一直想知道你何时回公司
I always wondered what time you got down to the office.
抑或你的隐形人唤醒了你
Or did that little man of yours pull you out of bed?
看更找我的
The janitor did.
他看见你在沿途留下血迹
Seems you leaked a little blood on the way in here.
对
Yeah.
这不出奇
Wouldn't be surprised.
我想向你解释狄氏案的内情
I wanted to straighten you out on that Dietrichson case.
我明白
So I gather.
你站在这里多久了  很久了
How long have you been standing there? Long enough.
难以置信  峰回路转的故事
Kind of a crazy story with a crazy twist to it.
你还未完全破解的故事
One you didn't quite figure out.
不可能每次都知道
You can't figure them all, Walter.
对  我猜你不会明白
That's right. I guess you can't at that.
我喃喃自语
Now I suppose I get the big speech...
字眼复杂难明
the one with all the two-dollar words in it.
我们讨论一下
Let's have it, Keyes.
华达  你全身湿透
Walter, you're all washed up.
谢谢  没所谓
Thanks, Keyes. That was short anyway.
我要叫医生来
I'm gonna call for a doctor.
为什么  为我治疗
What for? So they can patch me up?
令我康复  双脚站稳
So they can nurse me along till I get back on my feet?
然后我自己
So I can walk into that gas chamber up
走进毒气室
at San Quentin on my own power?
是不是  巴顿
Is that it, Keyes?
相差不远
Something like that.
我有另一个提议对
I've got a different idea. Yeah?
听着
Look, Keyes.
不如你回床上
Suppose you went back to bed and didn't find these cylinders...
假装没发现办公室的录音带
till tomorrow morning, when the office opens...
然后你想怎么做也可以
After that you can play it any way you like.
你可以为我做这件事吗
Would you do that much for me, Keyes?
给我一个好理由
Give me one good reason.
我要四小时才能到达目的地
I need four hours to get where I'm going.
你哪里也去不成
You're not going anywhere, Walter. You bet I am.
我可以越过边境  你没有机会
I'm going across the border. You haven't got a chance, Walter.
试试无妨
Good enough to try for.
你不可能越过边界
You'll never make the border. That's what you think.
是吗  看我的厉害
Just watch me.
你连升降机也去不成
You'll never even make the elevator.
再见
So long, Keyes.
喂
Hello...
派救护车到橄榄街太平大厦
send an ambulance to the Pacific Building on Olive Street.
对  叫警察同时来
Yeah. It's a police job.
你还好吗  华达  我很好
How you doing, Walter? Fine.
只是有人将升降机移开了
Only somebody moved the elevator a couple of miles away.
他们正赶来
They're on the way.
你知道为何无法破解这案件
You know why you couldn't figure this one, Keyes?
告诉你
I'll tell you.
因为你要找的人太近了
Because the guy you were looking for was too close.
他就坐在你办公桌对面
He was right across the desk from you.
比办公桌更接近
Closer than that, Walter.
我也爱你
I love you, too.